The plan for today is what I am gonna talk about
今天的计划就是我要谈的内容
is the topic of convolutional neural networks.
是卷积神经网络的主题。
So essentially, um, there's actually quite a lot of
所以基本上，嗯，实际上有很多
content in this lecture of different things that's good to know about,
本讲座中有关不同事物的内容，有待了解，
since essentially this is going to be learn about
因为基本上这将是要学习的
convolutional neural networks in one large bite for NLP.
卷积神经网络在一个大的咬合NLP。
So, um, bit on announcements,
那么，嗯，咬一下公告，
explain the general idea of convolutional neural networks,
解释卷积神经网络的一般思想，
and then for quite a bit of it,
然后相当一点，
I want to go through in sort of some detail to particular papers that made
我想详细介绍一下特定的论文
use of convolutional neural networks for
卷积神经网络的应用
text classification, sentence classification tasks.
文本分类，句子分类任务。
Um, the first is a sort of a pretty simple,
嗯，第一个是非常简单的，
um, CNN that was done in 2014,
嗯，CNN在2014年完成，
and then the second one is a
然后第二个是
way more complex CNN that was done much more recently in 2017.
更复杂的CNN，最近在2017年完成了更多。
Okay. But first, a couple of announcements.
好的。但首先是几个公告。
Um, firstly, the last reminder on the mid-quarter feedback survey.
嗯，首先是关于季度中期反馈调查的最后一次提醒。
So tons of you have done the- this already.
所以你们已经做了很多 - 这个。
Thank you, thank you very much.
谢谢，非常感谢。
Um, but if you'd still be putting it off till the very last minute, um,
嗯，但如果你还要把它推迟到最后一分钟，嗯，
tonight at midnight is your last chance, um,
今晚午夜是你的最后一次机会，嗯，
to fill in the mid-quarter survey to get your,
填写季度中期调查，以获得你的，
um, to give us feedback and to get your half-a-point.
嗯，给我们反馈并得到你的半点。
Um, okay. And then the other thing that you should be thinking about,
嗯，好的。然后你要考虑的另一件事，
and I know lots of you are thinking about
而且我知道很多你在考虑
since I spent three hours talking to people yesterday,
因为我昨天花了三个小时与人交谈，
um, is about final projects.
嗯，是关于最终的项目。
Um, and so make sure you've got some plans from that, um,
嗯，所以请确保你有一些计划，嗯，
in place for, um,
嗯，嗯，
04:00 p.m, uh, 04:30 p.m. Thursday.
星期四下午4点，呃，04：30
I mean, in particular as we've discussed, um,
我的意思是，特别是我们已经讨论过，嗯，
your- part of what you're meant to do this year is to have found some research paper,
你今年要做的部分就是找到一些研究论文，
have read it, and have a summary and thoughts as to how it can inform your work.
已经阅读过，并总结和思考如何为您的工作提供信息。
Um, and then just make sure you have in your calendars, um,
嗯，然后确保你的日历中有，嗯，
the final project poster session for CS224n,
CS224n的最终项目海报会议，
which is gonna be in the evening of Wednesday March 20th,
这将是3月20日星期三晚上，
and we're holding it at the Alumni Center.
我们在校友中心举办。
Okay. Um, one more sort of announcement or just general stuff to cogitate.
好的。嗯，还有一种声明，或者只是一般性的东西。
Um, so we're now officially in the second half of the class.
嗯，所以我们现在正式上半年级。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
there's sort of still a few things that we want to teach you that are sort of basic,
还有一些我们想要教给你的东西是基本的，
and actually convolutional neural networks is one of them.
实际上卷积神经网络就是其中之一。
But, I mean, nevertheless in the second half of the class, I mean,
但是，我的意思是，尽管如此，在课程的后半部分，我的意思是，
things start to change and we're hoping to much more, um,
事情开始改变，我们希望更多，嗯，
prepare you for being real deep learning NLP researchers or practitioners.
让您真正深入学习NLP研究人员或从业人员。
And so what does that mean concretely?
那具体是什么意思呢？
Well, the lectures start to be less
嗯，讲座开始少了
giving every detail of how to build a very basic thing,
详细介绍如何构建一个非常基本的东西，
and more giving you some ideas
还有更多给你一些想法
to sort of some of the work that's been done in different areas.
分类在不同领域完成的一些工作。
And so to the extent that there's something of interest or
所以，在某种程度上，有一些感兴趣或
rele- relevant to a project or things like that.
与项目或类似事物相关。
Um, the hope is that while you can take some initiative to
嗯，希望是你可以采取一些主动
find out more about some of the things that are being talked about.
了解有关正在谈论的一些事情的更多信息。
Um, also would really welcome any questions about things that people,
嗯，也非常欢迎任何有关人们的事情的问题，
um, would want to know more about.
嗯，想要了解更多。
And the other thing that you should know about
还有你应该知道的另一件事
deep learning is that once we get past the fundamentals,
深刻的学习是，一旦我们超越基本面，
a lot of the stuff we teach just isn't
我们教的很多东西都不是
really known science or things that people are sure of that,
真正知名的科学或人们确定的东西，
you know, most of what I'm teaching in the second half of the course is pretty
你知道，我在课程后半部分教授的大部分内容都很漂亮
much what people think is good practice in 2019.
人们认为2019年的良好做法。
But, you know, the fact of the matter is what people think is
但是，你知道，事情就是人们的想法
good practice in deep learning has been changing really rapidly.
深度学习的良好实践一直在迅速变化。
So if you go back even two years or definitely if you go back four years, right?
所以，如果你回去两年，或者如果你回去四年，那么对吗？
There's just a lot of different things that people used to believe,
人们过去常常相信很多不同的东西，
and now people have some different ideas as to what works best.
现在人们对于最有效的方法有不同的看法。
And it's perfectly clear that come 2021 or 2023,
2021年或2023年，非常清楚
there will be some different ideas again as to what,
对于什么，会有一些不同的想法，
um, people think is best.
嗯，人们认为最好。
So you sort of just have to accept that this is, um,
所以你只需要接受这是，嗯，
a nascent rapidly emerging field
一个新兴的新兴领域
and it's good to understand the fundamentals and how things fit together.
了解基本面和事物如何融合在一起是很好的。
But after that, quite a bit of the knowledge is this is what people
但在那之后，相当多的知识就是人们
think is good at the moment and it keeps evolving over time.
现在认为很好，并且随着时间的推移不断发展。
And if you want to stay in the field, or doing things with deep learning,
如果你想留在现场，或深入学习，
you kind of still have to keep up with how it changes.
你仍然需要跟上它的变化。
It's called lifelong learning these days.
这些天被称为终身学习。
It's a very trendy concept.
这是一个非常时髦的概念。
Um, and so as well as the lectures,
嗯，还有讲座，
this is also true for the assignments.
作业也是如此。
Um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
we've been trying to make the assignments so that they started off very introductory,
我们一直在努力完成任务，以便他们开始非常介绍，
and gradually started to use less scaffolding,
并逐渐开始使用较少的脚手架，
and we're going to hope to, um,
我们希望，嗯，
continue that, um, with the sort of less hand holding in assignment five.
继续说，嗯，在任务五中少拿手。
And, you know, I guess what we're hoping to do is prepare you
而且，你知道，我想我们希望做的就是为你做好准备
both for the final project and for real life.
无论是最终项目还是现实生活。
I guess I was making an analogy this morning,
我想我今天早上做了个比喻，
um, comparing this to the sort of intro CS sequence,
嗯，将其与介绍CS序列进行比较，
so when there's CS106A and B that have tons of scaffolding,
所以当CS106A和B有大量的脚手架时，
and then in CS107,
然后在CS107中，
you're meant to learn how to diagnose and solve problems
你的目的是学习如何诊断和解决问题
for yourself in a debugger that is kind of the same,
对于你自己在一个类似的调试器，
um, for neural networks that, you know,
嗯，对于神经网络，你知道，
for the early assignments, um, you know,
对于早期任务，嗯，你知道，
we've given you every bit of handholding here, all of
我们已经在这里给你提供了所有的支持
these tests to make sure every little bit of it is okay,
这些测试确保每一点都没关系，
and here's exactly how to structure things.
而这正是如何构建事物的。
But, you know, in the real world,
但是，你知道，在现实世界中，
um, you're only going to be able to build and use neural networks.
嗯，你只能建立和使用神经网络。
If you can figure out why they're not working
如果你能弄明白他们为什么不工作
and what you have to change to make them work.
你需要改变什么来使它们发挥作用。
And, you know, the truth is as I talked a bit about last week, you know,
而且，你知道，事实就是我上周谈了一下，你知道，
that's often well more than half of the job that it seems easy enough to stick down.
这通常超过工作的一半，似乎很容易坚持下去。
Here's my neural net and the pieces that make sense to me,
这是我的神经网络和对我有意义的碎片，
and then you can spend the remaining 80 percent of the time
然后你可以花费剩下的80％的时间
scratching your head wondering why it doesn't actually work well,
挠挠脑袋想知道为什么它实际上不能很好地工作，
and how you could change it to make it to work well.
以及如何改变它以使其运作良好。
Um, so, um, I confess that debugging neural nets can often be hard, but, you know,
嗯，所以，嗯，我承认调试神经网络往往很难，但是，你知道，
the goal is that you should actually learn something about doing it,
目标是你应该真正学到一些关于这样做的东西，
and that's kind of one of the learning goals of the course when it comes down to it.
当谈到它时，这就是课程的学习目标之一。
Um, final little advertisement.
嗯，最后的小广告。
If you feel like you'd like to read a book,
如果您觉得自己想读书，
um, just out this week,
嗯，本周刚出来，
there's a new book on natural language processing with PyTorch
有一本关于PyTorch自然语言处理的新书
by Delip Rao and Brian McMahan.
作者：Delip Rao和Brian McMahan。
Delip actually lives in San Francisco.
Delip实际上住在旧金山。
Um, so, um, if you want to,
恩，嗯，如果你愿意，
you can buy a copy of this, of course.
当然，你可以买一份。
But if you don't want to, um,
但如果你不想，嗯，
buy it and you feel like having a bit of a look through it, um,
买它，你觉得有点看看它，嗯，
the Stanford library is actually has a license to the O'Reilly's Safari Books collection.
斯坦福图书馆实际上拥有O'Reilly的Safari Books系列的许可证。
So you can start off at library.stanford.edu and read it for free.
所以你可以从library.stanford.edu开始并免费阅读。
There's one catch to this which is the library only has
这是图书馆唯一的一个问题
16 simultaneous licenses to Safari Books.
同时获得Safari Books的16个许可。
So if you'd also like your classmates to be able to read it for free,
所以，如果你也想让你的同学能够免费阅读，
it really helps if you remember to log out of Safari Books Online,
如果您记得退出Safari Books Online，这确实很有帮助，
um, when you're done looking at it.
嗯，当你看完它的时候。
Um, yes, so this is sort of a,
嗯，是的，所以这有点像，
I mean, in some sense,
我的意思是，从某种意义上说，
I hope you will feel if you look at this book,
我希望你能看到这本书，
"Boy, I already know most of that stuff already.
“男孩，我已经知道了大部分内容。
It's not a super advanced book.
这不是一本超级高级的书。
But it's a good well-written tutorial of how to do things with PyTorch and NLP."
但它是如何用PyTorch和NLP做好的精心编写的教程。“
If you don't feel like you know most of the stuff in this book,
如果您不想知道本书中的大部分内容，
you can let me know but I will be a little sad.
你可以让我知道，但我会有点难过。
Um, okay, um, yeah.
嗯，好的，恩，是的。
So, let, so starting into today.
所以，让我们开始吧。
Um, so, we spent a lot of time on
嗯，所以，我们花了很多时间
recurrent neural networks and they are great for many things.
循环神经网络，它们对很多东西都很好。
Um, but there's sort of some things that they're not so good at.
嗯，但有些事情他们并不擅长。
So, you know, we kind of might like to know about a phrase like my birth,
所以，你知道，我们可能想知道像我出生这样的短语，
or a bigger phrase like of my birth,
或者像我出生的更大的短语，
and there's sort of no independent, um,
并且有点没有独立，嗯，
representation of those spans in a recurrent neural network.
在递归神经网络中表示这些跨度。
We kind of get sort of prefixes of a whole sentence.
我们得到一整句的前缀。
And while we did, um, bidirectional, um,
虽然我们做了，嗯，双向，嗯，
recurrent neural networks, and you could say, 'Well,
反复神经网络，你可以说，'嗯，
wait a minute you could use it in both directions' and to some extent that's true.
等一下你可以在两个方向上使用它，并且在某种程度上这是真的。
We can get stuff from this direction and stuff from this direction,
我们可以从这个方向得到东西，从这个方向来看，
but we still kind of have sort of
但我们仍然有点像
whole sequences that go to one end of the sentence or another.
整个序列，直到句子的一端或另一端。
We don't just have pieces of sentences.
我们不只是有句子。
And often, we'd like to sort of work out meanings of pieces of sentences,
通常，我们想要解决一些句子的含义，
and so, we sort of have two problems here.
所以，我们在这里有两个问题。
We only have sort of initial and final sub-sequences.
我们只有一些初始和最终的子序列。
And also, if you look at these representations, like if you say,
而且，如果你看一下这些陈述，就像你说的那样，
take this last state as the representation of the meaning of this text.
把这个最后的状态作为本文意义的表示。
What you find out,
你发现了什么，
is it's very dominated by the meaning of
它是否被它的意义所支配
the most recent words and what they are trying to predict as to what comes after them,
最近的单词以及他们想要预测的内容是什么，
and that's part of the reason why I mentioned
这就是我提到的原因之一
last time in the question answering, um, lecture,
上一次回​​答问题，嗯，讲座，
the idea that well you can do better by having a sentinel and training
通过哨兵和训练你可以做得更好的想法
something that has attention over the whole, um, LSTM structure.
关注整个，嗯，LSTM结构的东西。
Okay. But today we're going to look at
好的。但今天我们要看一下
a different alternative which is convolutional neural nets,
一种不同的替代方案，即卷积神经网络，
which are often abbreviated as either CNN's or ConvNets.
它们通常缩写为CNN或ConvNets。
Um, and the idea of these is, well,
嗯，这些的想法是，嗯，
look maybe we could just take
看起来也许我们可以采取
every sub-sequence of a certain length and calculate a representation for it, um,
一定长度的每个子序列并计算它的表示，嗯，
so that, you know, if we have some piece of text like,
所以，你知道，如果我们有一些文字，比如
tentative deal reached to keep government open,
为保持政府开放达成初步协议
and we could sort of just say, well,
我们可以说，好吧，
let's just take all three words sequences,
让我们把所有三个单词序列，
tentative deal reached, deal reached to,
已达成暂定协议，达成协议，
reached to keep et cetera,
达到了保持等待，
and we're going to calculate some kind of representation for each of those sequences.
我们将为每个序列计算某种表示形式。
So, this is an- isn't a strongly linguistic idea.
所以，这不是一个强烈的语言观念。
Right? We're not worrying about whether it's a coherent phrase,
对？我们不担心它是否是一个连贯的短语，
that's grammatical linguistically valid,
这在语法上是有效的，
cognitively plausible, we're just taking every sub-sequence of a certain length.
在认知上看似合理，我们只是采取一定长度的每个子序列。
And then, once we've calculated representations of those,
然后，一旦我们计算了那些的表示，
we're going to look at how to group them.
我们将看看如何对它们进行分组。
Okay. So, let's get into more detail as to what CNN's are and how they work.
好的。那么，让我们详细了解CNN是什么以及它们是如何工作的。
Um, yeah, so, there's this general idea of a convolution which you may or may
嗯，是的，所以，你可能会或可能会有这种卷积的概念
not have seen in some math or electrical engineering class.
在某些数学或电气工程课上没见过。
And then, there's the particular version of convolutions,
然后，有特定版本的卷积，
the discrete convolutions, which you can means that
离散卷积，你可以这意味着
you can use the friendly summation symbol rather than an integral.
你可以使用友好的求和符号而不是积分符号。
Um, and that's a,
嗯，那是一个，
that's a discrete convolution.
那是一个离散的卷积。
I find that that notation as completely unhelpful.
我发现那种符号完全没有用。
So, I won't even try and explain it.
所以，我甚至不会尝试解释它。
But I've got lots of examples,
但我有很多例子，
and convolutions are really easy for neural nets in terms of what they do for examples.
就例子而言，神经网络和卷积非常容易。
All right, so the classic case of where convolutional neural networks are used,
好吧，所以使用卷积神经网络的经典案例，
is in vision applications.
在视觉应用中。
So, if you do CS231N next quarter,
所以，如果你下个季度做CS231N，
essentially you know,  the first four weeks is just all doing
基本上你知道，前四周就是全部
convolutional neural networks in all their variants and glory.
卷积神经网络的所有变体和荣耀。
Um, and the sort of essential idea of, um,
嗯，还有那种基本的想法，嗯，
convolutions for a vision,
有远见的卷积，
is that you want to recognize things no matter where they appear in an image.
是你想要识别的东西，无论它们出现在图像中的哪个位置。
So, you have a sort of property of translation and variance,
所以，你有一种翻译和变异的属性，
and the idea of a convolution as a way
以及卷积作为一种方式的想法
of finding something in different places in the image,
在图像中的不同位置找到某些东西，
regardless of where it appears.
无论它出现在哪里。
Um, so this is the vision example which I stole from Andrew Ng's UFLDL website.
嗯，所以这是我从Andrew Ng的UFLDL网站上偷走的视觉范例。
And so, what a convolution is,
那么，卷积是什么，
is it's here a patch,
它在这里是一个补丁，
but you can think of it as just as a vector,
但你可以把它想象成一个矢量，
and the patch has weights which are these little numbers in red,
补丁的重量是这些红色的小数字，
and what you're gonna do,
你要做什么
is slide that patch over the image as this as this animation does.
就像这个动画一样，在图像上滑动补丁。
Um, and so at each position,
嗯，在每个位置，
you're going to multiply each of the red numbers by the black number in that position,
你要将每个红色数字乘以该位置的黑色数字，
and then you're just going to sum them up.
然后你就是要总结它们。
So, that's what a discrete convolution does,
那么，这就是离散卷积的作用，
which is what that notation at the top is saying,
这是顶部的符号所说的，
right? You're multiplying things together and then you're summing them up,
对？你把事物放在一起，然后你就把它们相加，
and so you're doing this,
所以你这样做，
and then you're filling in the pink with the products,
然后你用产品填充粉红色，
um, the sum products.
嗯，和产品。
So, it's sort of like, you're taking these sort of
所以，有点像，你正在采取这种方式
patch dot products and putting them into the pink matrix,
补丁点产品并将它们放入粉红色矩阵中，
and that's then your convolved feature.
那就是你的卷积特征。
So, that's a 2D convolution,
那么，这是一个2D卷积，
which for the rest of today,
对于今天剩下的时间，
we're not going to look at anymore.
我们不会再看了。
So, this is all you're learning about vision.
所以，这就是你对视觉的了解。
Um, and so we're now going to go back and look at 1D convolutions,
嗯，所以我们现在要回去查看1D卷积，
which is what people use when they're using convolutional neural networks for text.
这是人们在使用卷积神经网络进行文本时使用的。
So, the starting point of a convolutional neural network for text,
那么，文本的卷积神经网络的起点，
is we have an input.
我们有一个输入。
So, here's my sentence and for each word
所以，这是我的句子和每个单词
in the sentence I have here got a dense word vector,
在这句话中我有一个密集的单词向量，
I made it a 4D, want to keep it small in my example but usually as you know, it's more.
我把它做成4D，想在我的例子中保持小，但通常如你所知，它更多。
So, our starting point is we have some input, you know,
所以，我们的出发点是我们有一些意见，你知道，
input could just be a one-hot encoding that's not forbidden here,
输入可能只是一个热门编码，这里不禁止，
but normally we'll have these kind of dense word vectors.
但通常我们会有这些密集的单词向量。
And so, then it's sort of the same as the 3D as the 2D one,
那么，它就像3D一样，与2D相同，
apart from we've only got one dimension.
除了我们只有一个维度。
So, we have a filter.
所以，我们有一个过滤器。
Um, so here is our filter,
嗯，这是我们的过滤器，
and so our filter is gonna do three steps and time, three words.
所以我们的过滤器会做三个步骤和时间，三个字。
And that's going to work across the dimensions.
这将跨越各个方面。
So, these different dimensions in
所以，这些不同的维度
the convolutional neural network often get referred to as channels.
卷积神经网络通常被称为信道。
So, we're kind of working across the input channels,
所以，我们在输入渠道上工作，
and so we have a patch like this.
所以我们有这样的补丁。
And we're going to take this patch and put it on top of the first three words.
我们将采用这个补丁并将其放在前三个单词之上。
I don't have as good an animation as the previous slide.
我没有上一张幻灯片那么好的动画。
Sorry. And we're going to work out the dot product,
抱歉。我们要研究点积，
um, between those, and I did that at home by putting this into Excel.
嗯，介于两者之间，我把它放在Excel中就是在家里做的。
And the answer [LAUGHTER] to that,
答案是[笑声]，
is that the product is minus 1,0.
是产品是负1,0。
And then at that point, we slide our,
然后在那一点上，我们滑动我们的，
We slide this, um,
我们滑了这个，嗯，
matrix which gets referred to as a kernel or
矩阵被称为内核或
a filter which is the patch that we're using for our convolutional neural network.
一个过滤器，它是我们用于卷积神经网络的补丁。
We slide it down one and do the dot product of those terms again.
我们将其向下滑动一次并再次执行这些术语的点积。
And that comes out as minus a half and we keep on sliding that down and we get what,
这个减半，我们继续向下滑动，我们得到了什么，
um, gets what's shown on the right as our output.
嗯，得到右边显示的输出。
So at this point,
所以在这一点上，
we've just reduced the sentence,
我们刚刚减刑，
um, to a single vector.
嗯，到一个向量。
Um, and that seems like we might want to do more than that.
嗯，这似乎我们可能想要做更多的事情。
Um, but the other thing that you will have noticed is that
嗯，但你会注意到的另一件事是
our sentence is sort of shrunk because before, you know,
我们的句子有点缩小，因为之前，你知道，
we had a seven word sentence but because I've just sort of slid this three word,
我们有七个字的句子，但因为我只是滑了这三个字，
um, kernel down here,
嗯，内核在这里，
I ended up with only five positions to put it in.
我最终只有五个职位才能投入。
So it's become a five word thing.
所以这成了一个五字的事情。
Um, so to first of all address that problem,
嗯，首先要解决这个问题，
commonly when people do convolutional neural networks, they add padding.
通常当人们进行卷积神经网络时，他们会添加填充。
Um, so what I can do is I can add zero padding at
嗯，所以我能做的就是我可以添加零填充
both ends and then sort of do the same trick and say run a convolution on that.
两端，然后做同样的伎俩，然后对此进行卷积。
And now, I'll be able to put my size three filter in seven different places as I
而现在，我将能够将我的尺寸三滤镜放在七个不同的地方
slide it down and so I'm getting out a vector that's the same length of my input.
向下滑动，所以我得到一个与我的输入长度相同的向量。
Um, that, you know, there are different way,
嗯，你知道，有不同的方式，
so this is the most common way of doing things.
所以这是最常见的做事方式。
And it's kind of seems logical because it maintains size.
这似乎是合乎逻辑的，因为它保持了规模。
I mean, you know, there's always more than one way to do it.
我的意思是，你知道，总有不止一种方法可以做到这一点。
Um, if you really wanted to,
嗯，如果你真的想，
you, oops, I don't want you, yeah,
你，哎呀，我不要你，是的，
there, oops, I made, uh,
在那里，哎呀，我做了，呃，
I made a slight mistake on my slide because this
我在幻灯片上犯了一个小错误，因为这个
turns out which I was about to get to in a minute
事实证明我将在一分钟内到达
but I'll just explain this bit here anyway [LAUGHTER].
但无论如何我都会在这里解释一下[笑声]。
Um, you know, if you wanted to,
嗯，你知道，如果你愿意，
you could have two steps of padding on both ends here.
你可以在这里两端填充两个步骤。
So that your first convolution we'll be looking at zero, zero,
所以你的第一个卷积我们将看零，零，
10 to the of and then the convolution would actually grow the size of your input.
然后卷积实际上会增加你输入的大小。
Yeah. But, yes. So I mean,
是啊。但是，是的。所以我的意思是，
so what we've done so far,
那么到目前为止我们做了什么，
we've started with these word vectors which in
我们已经开始使用这些单词向量
convolutional neural networks terms were of length four.
卷积神经网络术语长度为四。
So our kind of input had four channels.
所以我们的输入有四个渠道。
But when we were back here, um,
但是当我们回到这里时，嗯，
we were just producing from this, um,
我们刚从这里生产，嗯，
kernel, one column of output.
内核，一列输出。
So our output has only a single channel.
所以我们的输出只有一个通道。
So we've sort of shrunk things in the columns direction from four to one.
所以我们在列方向上从四个变为一个缩小的东西。
And that might seem bad.
这可能看起来很糟糕。
And for many purposes, it is bad.
而且出于许多目的，这很糟糕。
Um, and so, a lot of the time,
嗯，很多时候，
what you want to do is to say,
你想要做的是说，
well, rather than have only one filter,
好吧，而不是只有一个过滤器，
instead of that, why don't I have several filters?
而不是那个，为什么我没有几个过滤器？
So here I've got three different filters and each of
所以在这里我有三个不同的过滤器和每个
these filters is just sort of the same size three,
这些过滤器只是大小相同，
three the size, the kernel size times the input,
三个大小，内核大小乘以输入，
number of channels for the matrix.
矩阵的通道数。
So I have three different filters and I'm going to run
所以我有三个不同的过滤器，我将要运行
each one down the text and get a column here.
文本中的每一个都在这里得到一个列。
So now, I'm ending up with three columns of output.
所以现在，我最终得到了三列输出。
And so I have this sort of a three channel output.
所以我有这种三通道输出。
And the way to intuitively think of this is for these filters,
直观地考虑这个问题的方法是针对这些过滤器，
well, you know, for what we do in neural networks,
嗯，你知道，我们在神经网络中做了什么，
we're going to learn them by backpropagation like everything else.
我们将像其他一切一样通过反向传播来学习它们。
But our hope is that these filters could somehow specialize in different things.
但我们希望这些过滤器能以某种方式专注于不同的事物。
So maybe this filter could specialize on,
所以也许这个过滤器可以专注于，
is this language polite?
这种语言有礼貌吗？
And it will produce a high value whenever it sees polite words.
只要看到礼貌用语，它就会产生很高的价值。
And maybe, um, this, um,
也许，嗯，这个，嗯，
filter could specialize on, I don't know,
过滤器可以专攻，我不知道，
eating and it will have a high value whenever it sees words
吃东西，只要看到文字就会有很高的价值
about food and you know this filter will do a third thing.
关于食物，你知道这个过滤器会做第三件事。
And so that's the sense in which people sometimes talk about, um, the, um,
所以这就是人们有时会谈论的感觉，嗯，嗯，
what you're getting is output of different features because your hope is that
你得到的是不同功能的输出，因为你的希望就是这样
you'll kind of gain different latent features coming out of the text.
你会从文本中获得不同的潜在特征。
Okay. So that gives us a representation and that's sort of
好的。所以这给了我们一个代表，那就是那种
a useful sort of having found learn features in our text.
在我们的文本中找到学习功能的有用方法。
That quite often though, what we'll want to do is just
但这经常是我们想做的事情
summarize the text with re- with respect to those features.
关于这些特征重新总结文本。
So you might just have the question of, well,
所以你可能只是有一个问题，好吧，
in this piece of text, um,
在这篇文章中，嗯，
is it polite and does it talk about food?
它有礼貌吗？它谈论食物吗？
So another operation that we'll quite often
所以我们经常会进行另一项操作
do is wanna summarize the output of a convolutional network.
我想总结一个卷积网络的输出。
And the simplest way to do that,
最简单的方法，
is for 1D convolutions,
适用于1D卷积，
is called max pooling over time.
被称为最大池化随着时间的推移。
So if we max pool over time,
所以，如果我们最大化时间池，
that each of the channels or otherwise known as features,
每个频道或其他已知的功能，
we're just simply going to look down and see what is its maximum value, 0,3, 1,6, 1,4.
我们只是简单地向下看，看看它的最大值是什么，0,3,1,6,1,4。
Um, and so, you know,
嗯，你知道，
if I use my story about the first two, um,
如果我用我关于前两个的故事，嗯，
filters, it's sort of saying, well,
过滤器，有点说，好吧，
it's not very polite text but it's really about food, right?
这不是很有礼貌的文字，但它真的是关于食物，对吗？
That we're sort of summarizing,
我们总结一下，
um, what we've detected there.
嗯，我们在那里发现了什么。
Um, so the concept of max pooling in some sense captures,
嗯，所以在某种意义上捕获的最大池的概念，
does, is this thing being activated anywhere, right?
是的，这件事在任何地方都被激活了吗？
So if we have things like politeness and about food,
所以，如果我们有礼貌和食物，
that the output of max pooling will have a high value.
最大池的输出将具有高值。
If somewhere in the sentence there was a clear marker of
如果在句子的某个地方有明确的标记
politeness or something clearly about food.
关于食物的礼貌或清楚的事情。
And that's often a useful notion because often what you want to know is,
这通常是一个有用的概念，因为通常你想知道的是，
you know, is there some discussion of food in this sentence or is there not?
你知道吗，在这句话中是否有一些关于食物的讨论还是没有？
There's another thing, there are other things that you could do.
还有一件事，你还可以做其他事情。
Instead of, ah, max pooling,
而不是，啊，最大池，
you can instead do average pooling.
你可以改为平均合并。
So here you just take these numbers and find the average of them.
所以在这里你只需要取这些数字并找到它们的平均值。
That then has the different semantics which is sort of
那就有了不同的语义
what's the average amount of politeness of this, um,
这是什么礼貌的平均数，嗯，
text or on average how much, you know, how,
文字或平均多少，你知道，如何，
what percent of the sentence is about food or something like that.
这个句子的百分之几是关于食物或类似的东西。
Um, for some purposes,
嗯，出于某些目的，
this is better because, you know,
这更好，因为，你知道，
it takes in all of the important builds to an average.
它将所有重要的构建都纳入平均值。
I mean, a lot of the time,
我的意思是，很多时候，
people have found that actually max pooling is better because,
人们发现实际上最大池化更好，因为，
you know, a lot of signals in natural language are sparse.
你知道，很多自然语言的信号很稀疏。
You know, no matter how polite you are trying to be,
你知道，无论你多么有礼貌，
you're not going to be being polite in every word.
你不会在每个字中都礼貌。
You're going to say nouns and articles like that and a,
你会说那样的名词和文章，和
and prepositions and conjunctions,
和介词和连词，
none of which are inherently polite, right?
这些都不是礼貌的，对吧？
Um, so that if there's some politeness showing up prominently,
嗯，如果有一些礼貌出现突出，
then the sentence becomes polite and max pooling is actually better for capturing that.
然后句子变得有礼貌，而最大池化实际上更适合捕获它。
Um, of course the one other kind of thing that you can do as
嗯，当然是你能做的另一件事
min pooling and find the least [LAUGHTER] active thing.
min pooling并找到最少[LUGHTER]活跃的东西。
Um, it doesn't get used much but you could do that as well.
嗯，它没有得到很多使用，但你也可以这样做。
Okay. So, um, so if you're in PyTorch,
好的。所以，嗯，如果你在PyTorch，
this is all pretty easy stuff to do.
这都是非常容易的事情。
So there's a handy dandy Conv1d.
所以有一个方便的花花公子Conv1d。
There's also a Conv2d as you might guess for vision.
还有一个Conv2d，你可能会猜测它的愿景。
But there's a Conv1d, um,
但是有一个Conv1d，嗯，
where you're specifying how many input channels there are.
你在哪里指定有多少输入通道。
That was our word embedding size.
这就是我们的嵌入大小。
How many output channels there are?
有多少输出通道？
We have three.
我们有三个。
What the size of the convolutional kernel is?
卷积内核的大小是多少？
So the ones that we were showing were also
所以我们展示的那些也是
three and then there are various other parameters you can have.
三，然后你可以有各种其他参数。
Like you can say that you want a padding of one and things like that.
就像你可以说你想要一个填充和类似的东西。
And then once you've got one of those,
一旦你有其中一个，
you can just sort of run
你可以尝试一下
your convolutional filter on the input to get a new hidden state.
您对输入的卷积过滤器以获得新的隐藏状态。
And then if you wanna max pool,
然后，如果你想最大的游泳池，
you can just max,
你可以最多，
um, through the output of that and then you've got a max pooled output.
嗯，通过输出，然后你有一个最大池输出。
Okay. So that gives us the basics of building a kind of a convolutional neural network,
好的。这样就为我们提供了构建一种卷积神经网络的基础知识，
um, for, um, NLP.
嗯，因为，嗯，NLP。
Does that sort of makes sense up until there?
这有什么意义，直到那里？
Yeah. Okay. So next bit is to sort of show
是啊。好的。所以下一步就是要表现出来
you three or four other things that you can do.
你可以做三到四件其他事情。
Um, I started off typing these slides
嗯，我开始输入这些幻灯片
other less useful notions because I
其他不太有用的概念，因为我
kinda thought, oh, at least they don't really come up much in NLP.
有点想，哦，至少他们并没有真正在NLP中出现太多。
But, you know, actually it turned out when I got on to that second paper,
但是，你知道，实际上当我接到第二篇论文时，
when I say the complex convolutional neural network, actually,
当我说复杂的卷积神经网络时，实际上，
in that paper they try out just about all of these things that I say no one uses.
在那篇论文中，他们尝试了我说的没有人使用过的所有这些东西。
So it's sort of good to know what they are for looking at various papers.
因此，了解它们对于查看各种论文有什么好处。
So here, when we did things so far then we were calculating these convolutions,
所以在这里，当我们做到目前为止，我们正在计算这些卷积，
that we're sort of trying them out at every position.
我们在各个位置尝试它们。
So we had one for zero, tentative deal.
所以我们有一个零暂时的交易。
Then for tentative deal reached then deal reached to.
然后达成暂定交易，然后交易达成。
And so we were just walking down one step at
所以我们只是走了一步
a time which is referred to as a stride as, of one.
一个被称为步幅的时间。
And that's by far the most common thing to do.
这是迄今为止最常见的事情。
But you could observe,
但你可以观察到，
look wait a minute,
看一下，
since the first convolution concerns zero tentative deal.
因为第一次卷积涉及零暂定交易。
I've got all those three words in there.
我在那里得到了所有这三个字。
Even if I skip down to a next did, deal reach to and then I did to keep government,
即使我跳到下一个做了，交易到达，然后我做了保持政府，
I'd still have in one or other of the convolutions every word of the sentence
我仍然会在句子的每个单词中包含一个或另一个单词
so I can do half as much computation and I've
所以我可以做一半的计算而且我已经
still got everything in there in some sense.
在某种意义上，仍然有一切都在那里。
And so that's referred to as using a stride of two.
因此，这被称为使用两个步幅。
And so then I get something with half as many rows out.
然后我得到了一半的行数。
So it's one way to sort of compactify your representation and produce
因此，这是一种使你的表现和产生变得紧凑的方法
something shorter from a longer sentence and we'll see that use of it coming up later.
从较长的句子缩短的东西，我们会看到它的使用会在以后出现。
There's other ways to compactify what cut representation that comes out of your sentence.
还有其他方法可以减少从句子中删除表示的内容。
And so there's a different notion of pooling which is local pooling.
因此，有一种不同的汇集概念，即本地汇集。
Now, if if you've seen any of
现在，如果你看过任何一个
the vision world when people talk about max pooling and vision,
人们谈论最大汇集和视觉时的愿景世界，
they normally mean local pooling as opposed to
它们通常意味着本地汇集而不是
the max pooling through time that I showed you first.
我最初向你展示的最大汇集时间。
So here we're sort of back to where we started and we've done
所以在这里，我们回到了我们开始的地方，我们已经完成了
our size three stride one convolution which is producing output as before.
我们的规模是三步一个卷积，正如以前一样产生输出。
But now, what I'm gonna do is local pool with a stride of two.
但是现在，我要做的是本地游泳池，两步之遥。
Which means I'm gonna take each two rows and I'm gonna pool them together into
这意味着我要分两排，我要将它们组合在一起
one row and I could do that again by
一排，我可以再做一次
either maxing or averaging or whatever appeals to me.
无论是最大化还是平均或对我有什么吸引力。
So I take the first two rows,
所以我采取前两行，
I max pool them I get this.
我最大限度地利用它们我得到了这个
I take the next two rows,
接下两行，
I max pool them I get this.
我最大限度地利用它们我得到了这个
Next two, next two and I sort of pad it
接下来的两个，接下来的两个和我一样填补它
on the bottom so I have two rows at the bottom.
在底部，所以我底部有两排。
And so that's then give me a local max pooling of a stride of two.
所以那就是给我一个局部最大池的两个步幅。
And that sort of had exactly the same effect in the sense but
从某种意义上讲，这种效果完全相同
with a different result as using a stride of two in
使用两个步幅的结果不同
my convolution because I have again reduced it to
我的卷积因为我再次减少它
something of four rows that used to be eight rows.
曾经是八行的四行。
Yeah, picture that.
是的，想象一下。
Okay so that's that one.
好吧那就是那一个。
What else can you do.
你还能做什么。
There are more things you can do to make it complex.
你可以做更多的事情来使它变得复杂。
Another thing that people have sometimes done is k-max pooling.
人们有时做的另一件事是k-max汇集。
And so this is a more complex thing and it's sort of saying well,
所以这是一个更复杂的事情，它有点说得好，
rather than just keeping the max over time,
而不仅仅是保持最大值，
if a feature is being kind of activated two or three times in the sentence,
如果某个功能在句子中被激活了两三次，
maybe it'd be good to record all the times that it's
也许记录它的所有时间都是好的
activated in the sentence while throwing away the rest.
在抛弃其余部分的同时激活了句子。
So in k-max pooling,
所以在k-max汇集中，
and I'm doing two max here,
而我在这里做两个最大值，
you look down this column and you find the two highest values for that column.
你向下看这个列，你会发现该列的两个最高值。
But then you put the two highest values not in the order of highest to lowest,
但是你把两个最高值放在最高到最低的顺序，
but in the order in which they are in these columns.
但按照它们在这些列中的顺序排列。
So it's minus 0,2,
所以它是负0,2，
0,3 for this one and it's 1,6,
0,3这个，它是1,6，
0,6 for this one because it reflects the orders of the columns up above.
0,6这个因为它反映了上面列的顺序。
Okay. Almost done, one more concept.
好的。几乎完成了，还有一个概念。
This is another way of compressing data which is a dilated convolution.
这是另一种压缩数据的方法，这是一种扩张的卷积。
So if you have a dilated convolution,
所以，如果你有一个扩张的卷积，
so dilated convolution doing it over here doesn't really make sense but where you can use
因此在这里进行扩张卷积并不是真的有意义，而是你可以使用的地方
a dilated convolution is if I take this and put it through another convolutional layer,
如果我把它放到另一个卷积层，扩散的卷积是，
we can kind of have deep convolutional networks that have multiple convolutional layers.
我们可以拥有具有多个卷积层的深度卷积网络。
So the idea of a dilated convolution issue is you're gonna skip some of the rows.
所以扩张卷积问题的想法是你要跳过一些行。
So if you use a dilation of two starting at the top,
所以，如果你从顶部开始使用两个扩张，
you're going to take the first, third,
你要拿第一个，第三个，
and the fifth row and multiply them by my fil- sorry,
和第五行并将它们乘以我的过滤对不起，
I have different filters.
我有不同的过滤器。
Multiply them by my filters and then get the values that appear here.
将它们乘以我的过滤器，然后获取此处显示的值。
And then if stride as one,
然后如果迈出一步，
you'd then use, you would go on and sort of do the next spread out rows.
然后你会使用，你会继续做下一个展开的行。
And so this allows you to have convolutions that see
因此，这允许您有看到的卷积
a bigger spread of the sentence without having many parameters.
没有很多参数的句子扩大。
So you don't have to do things this way.
所以你不必这样做。
You could have said, look,
你可以说，看，
I could just instead have convolutions with a kernel size of five.
我可以改为使用内核大小为5的卷积。
And then they'd say five,
然后他们会说五个，
see five words in a row but then I'd be having
连续看五个字然后我会有
sort of bigger matrices to specify my feature.
一些更大的矩阵来指定我的功能。
Whereas, this way I can keep the matrices small but still
然而，这样我可以保持矩阵小但仍然
see a bigger range of the sentence in one operation.
在一次手术中看到更大范围的句子。
Yeah and that concept of how much of a sentence you
是的，那个概念你的判刑多少
see is kind of an important notion in convolutional neural networks.
在卷积神经网络中看到的是一种重要的概念。
Because, you know, if you start at the beginning of a sentence
因为，你知道，如果你从一个句子的开头开始
and you're just running three-by-three convolutions, um,
而你刚刚运行三乘三圈，嗯，
you're sort of seeing these three word patches of the sentence.
你有点看到这句话的三个单词补丁。
And it turns out in natural language that's
结果用自然语言证明了这一点
already actually quite a useful representation.
实际上已经非常有用了。
Because sort of having those kind of n-grams as features is
因为有那种n-gram作为特征是
just good for many purposes including text classification.
适用于包括文本分类在内的多种用途。
But if you want to sort of understand more of the semantics of a sentence,
但是如果你想要更多地理解一个句子的语义，
somehow you wanna see more of that at once.
不知何故，你想要立刻看到更多。
And you've sort of got several tools you can use to see more of it once,
而且你有一些工具可以用来看一次，
you can use bigger filters,
你可以使用更大的过滤器，
you could use, uh,
你可以用，呃，
kernel size five, seven,
内核大小五，七，
nine or something convolution.
九或其他卷积。
You could do something like dilated convolution so you can see spread out pictures.
你可以做一些像扩张卷积的事情，这样你就可以看到展开的图片。
And the third thing that you can do is you
你能做的第三件事就是你
can have depth of a convolutional neural network.
可以有卷积神经网络的深度。
Because as you have greater depth of a convolutional neural network, you see more.
因为你有更大的卷积神经网络深度，你会看到更多。
So at this first layer,
所以在第一层，
the rows now have sort of info about three words in them.
这些行现在有关于其中三个单词的信息。
And if you sort of just stuck a second layer of
如果你只是坚持第二层
convolutional neural network with
卷积神经网络
the same general nature on top of it and you sort of take
在它之上的相同的一般性质，你有点采取
the first three rows and convolve it again then and
前三行然后再次卷积它
then the next ones that those then know about five words of your original input sentence.
然后接下来那些那些知道原始输入句子的五个单词的人。
So as you kind of have a deeper ConvNet stack you
所以当你有更深层次的ConvNet堆栈时
start to know about bigger and bigger patches of the sentence.
开始了解句子越来越大的补丁。
Okay. All good?
好的。都好？
Any questions?
任何问题？
No, that's good, okay. So, um, the next piece is essentially shows you this stuff again,
不，那很好，没关系。所以，嗯，下一篇文章基本上再次向你展示这个东西，
um, in the context of a particular paper.
嗯，在特定论文的背景下。
So this was, um,
所以这是，嗯，
a paper by Yoon Kim who was a Harvard student,
Yoon Kim的一篇论文，是哈佛大学的学生，
maybe still is a Harvard student, um, in 2014.
也许在2014年仍然是哈佛大学的学生。
So this was sort of a fairly early paper.
所以这是一篇相当早期的论文。
Um, and he wanted to show that you could use convolutional neural networks to do
嗯，他想表明你可以使用卷积神经网络来做
a good job for doing
干得好
text classification when what you want to classify is a single sentence.
当您要分类的内容是单个句子时的文本分类。
So, the kind of thing you might want to do is look at the kind of
所以，你可能想做的事情就是看那种
snippets of movie reviews that you see on the Rotten Tomatoes site and say,
您在Rotten Tomatoes网站上看到的电影评论片段，并说，
"Is this a positive or is this a negative sentence description?"
“这是一个积极的还是一个负面的句子描述？”
And the model he built is actually kind of similar
他建造的模型实际上有点类似
to the convolutional neural networks that Collobert and Weston,
到Collobert和Weston的卷积神经网络，
um, introduced in their 2011 paper that we
嗯，在2011年的论文中介绍了我们
mentioned before when we were talking about window-based classifiers.
之前提到的当我们谈论基于窗口的分类器时。
So, in their paper they actually use
因此，在他们的论文中他们实际使用
both window-based classifiers and the convolutional classifier.
基于窗口的分类器和卷积分类器。
Okay. Um, so yeah,
好的。嗯，是的，
I sort of already said this.
我已经说过了。
So their tasks are sentence classification, could be sentiment.
所以他们的任务是句子分类，可能是情绪。
It could be other things like,
它可能是其他的东西，如，
is this sentence subjective or objective?
这句话主观还是客观？
So objective is what the main news articles are meant
所以客观是主要新闻文章的意思
to be and subjective is what the opinion pieces are meant to be.
是和主观的是意见的意图。
Um, and then other things like question classification.
嗯，然后其他的东西，如问题分类。
Is this a question asking about a person,
这是一个询问一个人的问题，
location, number, or whatever?
位置，数量或其他什么？
Okay, so here is what he did.
好的，所以这就是他所做的。
And it's sort of the- these slides sort of, um,
这有点像 - 这些幻灯片，嗯，
use the notation of his paper which is sort of a little bit different the
使用他的论文的符号，这有点不同
way the math gets written down to what I just showed
将数学写入我刚刚展示的内容的方式
you, that it's really doing exactly the same thing.
你，它确实在做同样的事情。
So we start with word vectors of length k. Um,
所以我们从长度为k的单词向量开始。嗯，
the sentence is made by just concatenating all of those word vectors together and then,
通过将所有这些单词向量连接在一起来制作句子，然后，
when we- so we have a range of words,
当我们 - 所以我们有一系列的话，
it's a subpart of that sentence vector.
它是该句子向量的子部分。
And so, the convolutional filter is just being represented as a vector because
因此，卷积滤波器只是表示为向量，因为
here he's flattened everything out into one long vector for the entire sentence,
在这里，他把一切都变成了整个句子的一个长向量，
whereas I'd sort of stepped into a matrix.
而我有点步入矩阵。
Um, so a size three convolution is just a real vector of length hk,
嗯，所以三个卷积只是一个长度为hk的真实矢量，
the size of the convolutional filter times the dimensionality of the words.
卷积滤波器的大小乘以单词的维数。
Um, and so, what he's gonna do to build
嗯，等等，他要做什么来建立
his text classifier is use convolutions made out of different sizes.
他的文本分类器是使用不同大小的卷积。
So you can have size two convolutions,
所以你可以有两个卷积，
size three convolutions as shown here, and bigger convolutions.
如此处所示的三个卷积，以及更大的卷积。
And so, um, so to compute a feature one channel for our CNN, we're
所以，嗯，所以为我们的CNN计算一个频道的功能，我们是
then doing a dot product between the weight vector of
然后在重量矢量之间做一个点积
the feature times this sub-sequence of the same terms,
该特征乘以相同术语的子序列，
and he sort of also put in a bias which I sort of omitted.
而且他也有点偏见，我有点遗漏。
Um, and then putting it through a non-linearity,
嗯，然后通过非线性，
um, which I wasn't doing either.
嗯，我也没做过。
Um, but as sort of we've seen a ton of.
嗯，但就像我们看到的那样。
Um, and so, what we're wanting to do is that's our,
嗯，等等，我们想要做的就是我们的，
um, feature and we want to, um,
嗯，功能，我们想，嗯，
do it through all this- for a feature of kernel size three,
通过这一切来实现 - 对于内核大小为3的特性，
we're gonna go all the way through the sentence.
我们要一路走完这句话。
The other thing he did though was slightly funnel funny is,
他做的另一件事虽然有点漏斗有趣，
his windows were sort of lopsided in the notation, right.
对，他的窗户在符号中有点不平衡。
There's a word and th- the,
有一个字，而且，
um, h minus 1 words to the right of it.
嗯，h减去它右边的1个单词。
So he has padding here just on the right end whereas
所以他在右边那边填充，而
most people do their convolutions symmetrically in both directions around things.
大多数人围绕事物在两个方向上对称地进行卷积。
Okay. And so, we're going to do that for a bunch of features or
好的。所以，我们将为一堆功能或者这样做
channels Ci and therefore compute
通道Ci因此计算
our convolved representations just as we've talked about.
正如我们所讨论的那样，我们一致的表达。
Okay. Um, then he does just what we talked about.
好的。嗯，那他就是我们所说的。
Um, there's max over time pooling in the pooling layer to capture
嗯，在池化层中有最大限度的时间汇集来捕获
the most relevant things and is giving us a single number for each channel.
最相关的事情，并为每个频道提供一个号码。
Um, and we have features that look at different that have different kernel sizes.
嗯，我们的功能可以看到具有不同内核大小的不同内容。
Um, here's one other idea he used which is possibly a neat idea.
嗯，这是他用过的另一个想法，这可能是一个很好的想法。
Um, he knows one of the things that you could even think about in various ways,
嗯，他知道你可以用各种方式思考的事情之一，
um, for say a question answering system among other things.
嗯，比如说回答系统等问题。
Um, and so he used pre-trained word vectors.
嗯，所以他使用预先训练过的单词向量。
Um, but what he did was he actually kind of doubled the word vectors.
嗯，但他所做的是他实际上有点加倍了矢量这个词。
So, for each word he had two copies of the word vector,
所以，对于每个单词，他都有两个单词vector，
and so you have sort of two channel sets and one set he
所以你有两个通道组和一组他
froze and the other one he fine tuned as he trained.
冻结了，另一个他在训练时很好地调整了。
So it's sort of he tried to get the best of both worlds of sort of fine tuning
因此，他试图充分利用这两种微调的世界
and not fine tuning and all that went into the max pooling operation.
并没有微调和所有进入最大池操作。
Okay. Um, so, after the max pooling we get out one number for each channel and so,
好的。嗯，所以，在最大池之后，我们为每个通道输出一个数字，所以，
um, he has something of three size convolutions, three,
嗯，他有三个大小的卷积，三个，
four, five, 100 features for each size.
每种尺寸有四个，五个，100个功能。
So we're getting out a vector of size,
所以我们得出一个大小的矢量，
um, 300 at that point,
嗯，那时300，
and at that point you're taking that final vector and just sticking it
那时候你正在拿最后的矢量并坚持下去
through a softmax and that's then giving your classification of the classes.
通过softmax，然后给出你的课程分类。
Um, so all of that can be summarized in this picture if it's big enough to sort of read.
嗯，如果它足够大，可以在这张图片中总结所有这些。
So, here's our sentence.
所以，这是我们的判决。
I like this movie very much,
我非常喜欢这部电影，
which has you know, our word embedding dimension is five,
你知道吗，我们的单词嵌入维度是五，
and so then doing it in this example,
然后在这个例子中做，
we are having two channels for each kernel size and
我们每个内核大小都有两个通道
we consider kernels of size two, three, and four.
我们考虑大小为2,3和4的内核。
Um, and so and then we are getting two different ones.
嗯，等等我们得到两个不同的。
Um, so we're getting, um, six.
嗯，所以我们得到了，嗯，六岁。
This is showing six of our filters.
这显示了我们的六个过滤器。
Um, so we apply those.
嗯，我们应用那些。
When we- when we apply those filters without any padding,
当我们 - 当我们应用这些过滤器而没有任何填充时，
we are then getting out these outputs of the filters which are of sizes four,
然后我们将这些尺寸为4的滤波器的输出输出，
five, and six respectively.
五，六分别。
Um, and so then once we've got these
嗯，等我们有了这些
for each of these sets of numbers we're doing one max pooling.
对于这些数字中的每一组，我们都在进行一次最大池化。
So, we're just taking the max of each of these,
所以，我们只是采取其中的每一个，
um, output features which gives us these six numbers.
嗯，输出功能给我们这六个数字。
Um, we can concatenate them all together into one vector which we feed into,
嗯，我们可以将它们连接成一个载入的载体，
um, a softmax over two classes as to whether sentiment is positive or negative.
嗯，关于情绪是积极的还是消极的两个类别的softmax。
Um, so that's basically the model.
嗯，这基本上就是模特。
So something- so this is sort of really actually a very simple,
所以有点 - 所以这实际上非常简单，
very computationally efficient, uh,
计算效率很高，呃，
model as to how to build a text classifier.
关于如何构建文本分类器的模型。
[NOISE] Um, yeah, just a couple more things to get through,
[NOISE]嗯，是的，还有几件事可以通过，
um, so in one of the assignments,
嗯，所以在其中一个任务中，
we talked about Dropout [NOISE] and you used it.
我们谈到Dropout [NOISE]并且你使用它。
So, um, you know,
所以，嗯，你知道，
hopefully you're all masters of Dropout at this point.
希望你在这一点上都是Dropout的主人。
Um, so he was using Dropout, um,
嗯，所以他正在使用Dropout，嗯，
and this being 2014 and the,
这是2014年和
um, Dropout paper only coming out in 2014.
嗯，Dropout论文仅在2014年问世。
I guess, there'd been an earlier version that came out a couple of years earlier.
我想，早在两年前出现的早期版本。
This was sort of still fairly early,
这还有点早，
um, to be taking advantage of Dropout.
嗯，要利用Dropout。
So that while training,
所以在训练时，
you've got this sort of Dropout vector, um,
你有这种Dropout矢量，嗯，
where you sample your Bernoulli random variables and you're, sort of,
你在哪里采样你的伯努利随机变量，你有点像，
um, sort of, designed to drop out some of the features each time you are doing things.
嗯，有点像，每次你做事时都会删掉一些功能。
At testing time, you don't do the dropout,
在测试时，你不做辍学，
but because before you were sort of dropping out a lot of stuff,
但是因为在你贬低很多东西之前，
you're scaling your weight matrix by the same probability that you use for dropping out,
你按照与辍学相同的概率缩放你的体重矩阵，
so that you get, sort of,
所以，你得到，有点，
vectors of the same scale as before.
与之前相同比例的向量。
Um, so as we sort of discussed in the assignment,
嗯，正如我们在作业中讨论的那样，
Dropout is a really effective form of regularization,
辍学是一种非常有效的正规化形式，
widely used in neural networks.
广泛用于神经网络。
Um, he didn't only do that, he actually did,
嗯，他不仅这样做，他实际上做到了，
a kind of another sort of funky form of regularization.
一种另类的时髦形式的正规化。
So that's for the softmax weight vector,
这就是softmax权重向量，
he constrained the L2 norms,
他限制了L2规范，
so the squared norms of the weight vectors and the softmax, [NOISE] um,
所以权重向量的平方范数和softmax，[NOISE]嗯，
matrix, um, to a fixed number S,
矩阵，嗯，到一个固定的数字S，
which was sort of set of the hyper-parameters,
这是一组超参数，
actually set to the value three.
实际上设置为值三。
Um, and if your weights were getting too large,
嗯，如果你的体重太大，
they were being rescaled,
他们正在重新调整，
um, so they didn't blow up.
嗯，所以他们没有爆炸。
Um, this isn't a very common thing to do.
嗯，这不是很常见的事情。
I'm not sure it's very necessary, um, but, um,
我不确定这是非常必要的，嗯，但是，嗯，
I guess it gives you some- I mean,
我猜它会给你一些 - 我的意思是，
I guess by showing you a few of the details of this one,
我想通过向您展示这一个的一些细节，
my hope is, sort of,
我希望，有点像，
gives you some ideas about how there are lots of things you can play
给你一些关于你可以玩很多东西的想法
around with and muck with if you wanna try different things,
如果你想尝试不同的东西，周围和粪便，
um, for your final projects.
嗯，对于你的最终项目。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So here are some of his final hyperparameters.
所以这里是他最后的一些超参数。
So he's using ReLU nonlinearities,
所以他正在使用ReLU非线性，
um, window sizes of three, four, and five,
嗯，窗户大小有三个，四个和五个，
the convolutions, hundred features or channels for each size,
每种尺寸的卷积，百种特征或通道，
um, Dropout of a half as usual.
嗯，像往常一样辍学一半。
Um, you get several percentage improvements from dropout,
嗯，你从辍学中获得了几个百分点的改进，
which is quite common actually.
这实际上很常见。
Um, the sort of L2 constraint, s equals three,
嗯，这种L2约束，s等于三，
mini batch of 50,
迷你批次50，
300 dimensional word vectors,
300维词向量，
train to maximize dev set performance.
训练以最大化开发设置性能。
Okay. And here is the big table,
好的。这是大桌子，
you know, I was too lazy, um,
你知道，我太懒了，嗯，
to redo of performance on these different text classification data sets.
重做这些不同文本分类数据集的性能。
Um, there are lots of different ones.
嗯，有很多不同的。
So these two are both Stanford Sentiment Treebank.
所以这两个都是Stanford Sentiment Treebank。
This is the Subjective Objective Language.
这是主观客观语言。
This is the Question Classification, of is it asking for a person name and location,
这是问题分类，是要求人名和位置，
a company or whatever.
公司或其他什么。
Um, this is, um,
嗯，这是，嗯，
talking about, sort of, a perspective,
谈论，某种，一种观点，
which is another classification thing.
这是另一个分类的事情。
Consumer Reports is another sentiment one.
消费者报告是另一种观点。
Um, so lots of data sets and then here are lots of models.
嗯，所以有很多数据集，然后是很多模型。
So the model- some of the models down here or here,
所以模型 - 这里或这里的一些模型，
are traditional feature-based, um, classifiers.
是传统的基于特征的，嗯，分类器。
Um, so in particular,
嗯，特别是，
um, sort of Wang and me back in 2012,
嗯，有点像王和我回到2012年，
had sort of pointed out that by taking certain steps
有点指出通过采取某些步骤
with n-gram features and other forms of normalization,
具有n-gram特征和其他形式的规范化，
that you could actually get quite good results with
你实际上可以获得相当不错的结果
just the traditional feature, um, based classifiers.
只是传统的功能，嗯，基于分类器。
So many people use that as a baseline for showing that you can do better things.
很多人用它作为表明你可以做得更好的基线。
Um, the ones up here,
嗯，那里的人，
were tree structured neural networks that my group was very fond
是我的小组非常喜欢的树状结构神经网络
of in the early 2010s and then up at the very top,
在2010年初，然后在最顶端，
uh, his CNN models.
呃，他的CNN模特。
And as you can see,
正如你所看到的，
it's sort of a mix.
这是一种混合。
Sometimes the CNN model wins,
有时CNN模型获胜，
like in this column and this column,
就像在本专栏和本专栏中一样，
sometimes it doesn't win like in these columns.
有时它不像在这些专栏中那样获胜。
Um, but in general, um,
嗯，但总的来说，嗯，
what you didn't see from this is that, you know,
从这里你没有看到的是，你知道，
this is an extremely simple, um,
这是一个非常简单的，嗯，
convolutional neural network model and it actually does,
卷积神经网络模型，它实际上，
um, kind of well on this system.
嗯，在这个系统上很好。
Um, you can quibble with this results table,
嗯，你可以用这个结果表狡辩，
and again in terms of like writing your propos- project proposal, um,
再次就像写你的提案 - 项目提案一样，嗯，
one thing that you should do is kind of think about what you're reading, um,
你应该做的一件事就是想想你正在读什么，嗯，
because, you know, a lot of papers aren't perfect
因为，你知道，很多论文并不完美
and there are reasons to quibble with what they claim.
并且有理由对他们声称的东西嗤之以鼻。
And sometimes if you think about what they're claiming and whether it's reasonable, um,
有时如果你想到他们所声称的东西以及它是否合理，嗯，
there are reasons why it's not or there are ideas
有理由说它没有或有想法
of how you could do things differently or show something different.
如何以不同的方式做事或展示不同的东西。
I mean, the main reason why you could quibble with,
我的意思是，你可以狡辩的主要原因，
um, Yoon Kim's results table is, well,
嗯，Yoon Kim的结果表是，好吧，
he already said, as I had a couple of slides back, um,
他已经说过，因为我有几张幻灯片，嗯，
that the statement that Dropout gives you
Dropout给你的声明
two to four percent accuracy improvement in this neural nets.
这种神经网络的准确度提高了2％到4％。
[NOISE] Um, but most of these systems because they
[NOISE]嗯，但这些系统大部分都是因为它们
are older and were done before Dropout was invented,
在Dropout发明之前就已经过时了，
um, didn't make use of Dropout.
嗯，没有使用Dropout。
But, you know, any of these sort of neural net systems up here
但是，你知道，这里有任何一种神经网络系统
could have used Dropout and presumably it would have given them a couple of,
本来可以使用Dropout，可能会给他们一些，
um, percent gain as well.
嗯，百分比增益。
So arguably, this is sort of a biased, unfair comparison.
可以说，这是一种偏颇的，不公平的比较。
And the right thing would have been to be comparing all the systems, um, using Dropout.
正确的做法是使用Dropout比较所有系统。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
despite that, you know,
尽管如此，你知道，
this was still a prett- a lot of people noticed
这仍然是一个很多人注意到的
this paper because it showed that using this sort of very simple,
本文因为它表明使用这种非常简单，
very fast convolutional architecture,
非常快速的卷积架构，
could give you strong results for text classification.
可以为您提供强大的文本分类结果。
Um, that's that.
嗯，就是这样。
Yes. So in summary,
是。总而言之，
you know, something that you should be thinking about for projects and otherwise,
你知道，你应该考虑的项目和其他方面，
we're effectively building up a bigger toolkit of different tools you could be using,
我们正在有效地构建一个更大的工具包，可以使用不同的工具，
um, for projects or future work or whatever it is.
嗯，对于项目或未来的工作或其他任何工作。
So starting off with,
所以从开始，
we had word vectors and then we could build bag of
我们有单词向量，然后我们可以建立袋子
vector models by just taking the word vectors and averaging them.
矢量模型只需采用单词向量并对它们求平均值。
And, you know, that's actually a surprisingly good baseline to start with.
而且，你知道，这实际上是一个令人惊讶的良好基线。
We suggest to you in many cases for things like projects,
在很多情况下，我们建议你做项目，
you should use that.
你应该使用它。
See how well it does,
看它有多好，
make sure you're working better.
确保你的工作做得更好。
I mean particularly, you can do even better with that,
我的意思是，你可以做得更好，
if you sort of add some extra ReLU layers on top,
如果你在顶部添加一些额外的ReLU层，
which is an idea that's been explored in deep averaging networks.
这是一个在深度平均网络中探索过的想法。
Um, then we looked at window models which were very simple.
嗯，然后我们看了很简单的窗口模型。
You're just taking these sort of
你只是采取这种方式
five word windows and computing a feed-forward network on them,
五个字窗口并计算它们的前馈网络，
and they work very well for word classification problems that only need local context.
它们非常适用于只需要本地环境的单词分类问题。
Things like, part of speech tagging or NER.
比如，词性标注或NER。
But then we've gone ahead and looked at some other models.
但后来我们继续前进并研究了其他一些模型。
And so, um, CNN's are very good for text classification, um,
所以，嗯，CNN非常适合文本分类，嗯，
and they're very good because they parallelize really well on GPUs,
它们非常好，因为它们在GPU上非常好地并行化，
which is something I'll come back to again later.
这是我稍后会再回来的。
So they, they just sort- the general sort of representing sentence meaning.
所以他们，他们只是排序 - 代表句子意义的一般类型。
They're actually a efficient,
他们实际上是一个有效的，
versatile, good method, which has been used quite a bit.
多功能，好方法，已经使用了很多。
And then they sort of contrast with recurrent neural networks.
然后它们与递归神经网络形成鲜明对比。
Recurrent neural networks have some advantages.
递归神经网络具有一些优点。
They're sort of more cognitively plausible,
它们在认知上更合理，
because you're sort of reading through the text and,
因为你有点阅读文字，
um, getting its meaning.
嗯，得到它的意义。
Um, recurrent neural networks are good for
嗯，反复神经网络是有益的
things like sequence tagging and classification,
序列标记和分类之类的东西，
building language models to predict what's coming next.
建立语言模型来预测接下来会发生什么。
Um, they can do really well when combined with attention.
嗯，结合注意力，他们可以做得很好。
Um, but they also have some disadvantages.
嗯，但他们也有一些缺点。
They're way slower than convolutional neural networks and if what you wanna
它们比卷积神经网络慢，如果你想要的话
do is get out some kind of overall meaning representation of a sentence,
做出某种句子的整体意义表示，
you know, "What does this mean?
你知道吗，“这是什么意思？
Are these two, um,
这两个，嗯，
phrases paraphrases with each other?"
短语相互解释？“
There are now many results that show that people
现在有很多结果表明人
don't get better results with recurrent neural networks.
使用递归神经网络不会得到更好的结果。
They can get better results using techniques like convolutional neural networks.
使用卷积神经网络等技术可以获得更好的结果。
Okay. [NOISE] So in the next step then [NOISE] is to,
好的。 [NOISE]所以在下一步，[NOISE]是，
sort of, head towards our com- our complex,
走向我们的复杂，
um, convolutional architecture example.
嗯，卷积架构的例子。
So before getting to that,
所以在开始之前，
I just wanna sort of introduce a few concepts that we haven't seen,
我只是想介绍一些我们没见过的概念，
all of which, um, start to turn up when we do this.
当我们这样做时，所有这些，嗯，开始出现。
So we spent a lot of time in the sequence models part,
所以我们在序列模型部分花了很多时间，
talking about gated models or the gated recurrent units and the LSTM units.
谈论门控模型或门控循环单元和LSTM单元。
But the idea of a gate is general that we can
但是门的概念是我们可以做到的
sort of have this idea that we can calculate something,
我有这个想法，我们可以计算一些东西，
put it through, um,
把它穿过，嗯，
a sigmoid nonlinearity and gets a value between zero and one,
一个sigmoid非线性并得到一个介于0和1之间的值，
um, or a vector of values between zero and one.
嗯，或者介于0和1之间的值向量。
And then do a Hadamard product with a vector
然后用矢量做一个Hadamard产品
and sort of gate it between its value and zero.
并在它的值和零之间对它进行排序。
So that suggests the idea that you could also apply
所以这表明你也可以申请
gates vertically when you're building multilayer networks.
在构建多层网络时垂直关闭。
And after the successive LSTMs had been proven,
在连续的LSTM被证实之后，
that was, um, an idea that really took off,
那是，嗯，一个真正起飞的想法，
was people start exploring,
人们开始探索，
how can we have, use these ideas of skip connections and gating in a,
我们怎样才能使用跳过连接和门控的这些想法，
in a vertical direction?
在垂直方向？
And here are two versions of it.
以下是它的两个版本。
This one is a very simple one,
这是一个非常简单的，
but a very successful one that's basically just about a skip connection.
但是一个非常成功的，基本上只是跳过连接。
So and this is referred to as a residual block and- which is used in residual networks,
所以，这被称为残差块，用于剩余网络，
otherwise known as ResNets.
也称为ResNets。
Um, so in a residual block, for each block,
嗯，所以在剩余的区块中，每个区块，
you allow a value just to skip ahead to the next, um, layer.
你允许一个值只是跳到下一个，嗯，图层。
Or you can stick it through a conv block,
或者你可以把它粘在一个转子块上，
and the typical conv block is you go through a convolutional layer,
典型的转换块是你通过卷积层，
you then go through a ReLU nonlinearity,
然后你会经历ReLU非线性，
another convolutional layer, and then when you come out,
另一个卷积层，然后当你出来时，
you just sum these two values.
你只需将这两个值相加。
So this is the same idea that sort of
所以这就是那种想法
summing values is magical in the same way as an LSTM.
求和值与LSTM一样神奇。
And then you put the output of that through another ReLU,
然后你把它的输出通过另一个ReLU，
and this thing here is called a residual block
这件事叫做残余块
and then commonly you'll stack residual blocks on top of each other.
然后通常你会将剩余的块堆叠在一起。
Um, there's one little trick here,
嗯，这里有一个小技巧，
um, which is you need to use padding, right?
嗯，你需要使用填充，对吗？
Um, because at the end of the day since you want to sum these two pathways,
嗯，因为在你想要总结这两条路径的那一天结束时，
you want them to be the same size.
你希望它们的大小相同。
And if you, sort of,
如果你，那种，
have them shrinking in the conv blocks you wouldn't be able to sum them.
让它们在转换块中缩小，你将无法对它们求和。
So you want to, sort of, have a padding at each stage so they stay the same size here,
所以你想要，在每个阶段都有一个填充，所以它们在这里保持相同的大小，
and so that you can add them together.
这样你就可以把它们加在一起了。
Um, here's, um, a different version of a block which is
嗯，这是，嗯，是一个不同版本的块
sort of more LSTM-ish and indeed
更多LSTM-ish确实如此
this block was developed by Jürgen Schmidhuber and students,
这个街区是由JürgenSchmidhuber和学生们开发的，
who's the same guy who's behind LSTMs and you can see the same thinking.
谁是LSTM背后的同一个人，你可以看到同样的想法。
It's called a highway block.
它被称为高速公路街区。
So in a way it's sort of similar.
所以在某种程度上它有点类似。
You've got, you know, kind of thinking of moving an identity x that skips
你知道，你已经开始考虑移动跳过的身份x了
a nonlinear block or you can have it go through exactly the same stuff conv, relu, conv.
一个非线性块或者你可以让它通过完全相同的东西conv，relu，conv。
The difference is that unlike this one,
与众不同的是，
this time there's explicit gates so there's,
这次有明确的门，所以有，
um, and this T-gate and the C-gate.
嗯，这个T门和C门。
And so you're multiplying both of the path through here and the path through here
所以你将这里的路径和通过这里的路径相乘
by a gate just kinda like the sort of
通过一个门就像那种
the get input gates that we saw before and then summing them together.
我们之前看到的获取输入门然后将它们加在一起。
So that sort of feels more
所以那种感觉更多
powerful but it's not actually clear that it is more powerful.
功能强大，但实际上并不清楚它是否更强大。
I mean, this one actually has a very simple
我的意思是，这一个实际上非常简单
semantic because if you think of the semantics of this one
语义，因为如果你想到这个语义
is the default is just you walk
是默认只是你走
this way and you just sort of carry forward your value and do nothing.
通过这种方式，你只需要发扬自己的价值，什么都不做。
Um, so, what this block's job to- is to do,
嗯，这个街区的工作要做什么，
is to learn a delta that is meant to learn
是学习一个有待学习的三角洲
what kind of deviation you have from doing nothing.
什么样的偏离你什么都不做。
Um, so that's a nice simple semantic which, um,
嗯，这是一个很好的简单语义，嗯，
seems to work well in neural networks to learn things.
似乎在神经网络中很好地学习东西。
Um, this sort of has
嗯，这种有
more complicated apparent semantics because you're taking, you know,
更复杂的表观语义，因为你正在服用，你知道，
some parts of the identity multiplying by this sort of gate in a Hadamard product
身份的某些部分乘以Hadamard产品中的这种门
and some parts of this conv block multiplied by this other gate T in a Hadamard product.
这个转子块的某些部分乘以Hadamard产品中的另一个门T.
So that sort of feels more powerful as that
所以那种感觉更强大
gives me a lot more control because I can take pieces of the different ones and so on.
给了我更多的控制权，因为我可以采取不同的部分，等等。
If you think about it for a bit longer, I mean,
如果你再考虑一下，我的意思是，
mathematically it's actually not any more powerful that you
从数学上讲，它实际上并不比你更强大
can represent anything you can do with this one with that one.
可以代表任何你可以用这个做的事情。
And the way to think about that is well, um,
思考这个问题的方法很好，嗯，
you know, here you're kind of keeping only part of the identity,
你知道，在这里你只保留一部分身份，
um, but what you could do is keep the whole of the identity and see it as your job
嗯，但你能做的就是保持整个身份并将其视为你的工作
to subtract off the bits that this one isn't keeping
减去这个没有保留的位
over here in the conv block which you can do theoretically.
在这里你可以理论上做的转换块。
Um, and so, you can sort of anything you can compute with this as a function,
嗯，等等，你可以用它作为一个函数计算你可以计算的任何东西，
you can actually compute with a, um, ResNet block.
你可以用一个，嗯，ResNet块实际计算。
Um, and so then as quite often in neural network land,
嗯，然后经常在神经网络领域，
the question isn't sort of, um,
问题不是那种，嗯，
some kind of proof of compute- can be computed or not.
某种计算证明 - 可以计算或不计算。
It sort of comes down to learning and regularization questions as to
这有点归结为学习和正规化问题
whether one or the other of these actually proves
这些中的一个或另一个是否真正得到证实
better as something to use in a learning architecture.
更好地作为学习架构中使用的东西。
Okay. Second concept.
好的。第二个概念。
Um, batch normalization.
嗯，批量标准化。
So when people are building deep convolutional neural networks,
所以当人们建立深度卷积神经网络时，
um, in the 2015 pluses,
嗯，在2015年的时候，
um, they almost always use batch normalization layers because
嗯，他们几乎总是使用批量标准化层，因为
this makes your life a lot better and if they're not using batch normalization layers,
这会让你的生活变得更好，如果他们不使用批量标准化层，
they're normally using one of the other variant ideas that people have suggested
他们通常使用人们建议的其他变体想法之一
such as layer normalization which is sort of meant to do about the same thing.
例如层标准化，这有点意味着做同样的事情。
Um, so what batch normalization does?
嗯，那批量标准化呢？
I mean, I think many of you will have seen somewhere in steps or
我的意思是，我想你们中的许多人会看到某个地方或者步骤
otherwise the idea of doing a Z-transform which means you take your data,
否则做Z变换的想法意味着你拿走你的数据，
you work out its mean and you work out its
你弄清楚它的意思，你就可以解决它的问题
standard deviation and then you rescale by subtraction and
标准偏差然后通过减法和重新缩放
multiplication so that you have a set of data which
乘法使你有一组数据
has a mean of zero and a standard deviation of one.
平均值为零，标准差为1。
Most people see that, right?
大多数人都看到了，对吗？
Yeah? Um, so batch normalization is effectively doing exactly that but in a weird way.
是吗？嗯，所以批量标准化实际上正是这样做的，但是以一种奇怪的方式。
So what you're doing is that you're taking each mini batch.
所以你正在做的是你正在服用每一个小批量。
So whatever just random 32 examples you've stuck in a mini batch,
所以无论是随机的32个例子，你都陷入了迷你批次，
you're running them through a layer of
你正在通过一层运行它们
your neural network like a ConvBlock that we saw before
你的神经网络就像我们之前看到的ConvBlock一样
and you take the output of that mini batch and then you do a Z-transform on it.
并获取该迷你批次的输出，然后对其进行Z变换。
Um, and then it goes forward into the next ConvBlock or whatever,
嗯，然后它进入下一个ConvBlock或其他什么，
and the next time you have a different mini batch,
并且下次你有一个不同的迷你批次，
you just Z-transform it.
你只是对它进行Z变换。
So it seems a little bit weird.
所以看起来有点奇怪。
You're just doing it on the output of these mini batches.
你只是在这些迷你批次的输出上做这件事。
Um, but that's proven to be a very effective thing to do.
嗯，但事实证明这是一件非常有效的事情。
So that it sort of means that what comes out of
所以它有点意味着什么出来的
a ConvBlock sort of always has the same kind of scale.
ConvBlock总是具有相同的规模。
So it doesn't sort of fluctuate a lot and mess things up and it tends to
所以它并没有那么多波动并且搞砸了，而且往往会
make the models just much more reliably trainable because,
使模型更可靠地训练，因为，
you know, you just have to be much less fussy about a lot of things.
你知道，你必须对很多事情不那么挑剔。
Because, you know, a lot of the things we've talked about,
因为，你知道，很多我们谈过的事情，
about initializing your parameters and
关于初始化你的参数和
setting your learning rates is sort of about, well,
设定你的学习率有点嘛，好吧，
you have to keep the scale of things about right so they don't get
你必须把事情的规模保持正确，这样他们才能得到
too big or too small and things like that.
太大或太小等等。
Whereas, if you're doing this batch normalization,
然而，如果你正在进行这种批量标准化，
you're sort of forcing scale,
你有点强迫规模，
um, to being the same size each time.
嗯，每次都是相同的大小。
And s o therefore, you kind of don't have to do
因此，你有点不必做
the other stuff as well and it still tends to,
其他的东西，它仍然倾向于，
um, work pretty well.
嗯，工作得很好。
So that's a good technique to know about.
所以这是一个很好的技术来了解。
Okay. Um, one last thing to learn about.
好的。嗯，最后要了解的一件事。
Um, there's a concept of,
嗯，有一个概念，
um, size one convolutions.
嗯，一个卷积。
Um, and actually, I guess I really sort of, um,
嗯，实际上，我想我真的那样，嗯，
renamed it- I named this wrong because I wrote down
重命名它 - 我把它命名为错，因为我写下了
one by one convolutions because that's the term you normally see.
一个接一个的卷积，因为这是你通常看到的术语。
But that's, um, the vision world where you have 2D convolutions.
但那是，嗯，你有二维卷积的视觉世界。
So I guess I should have just called this one convolutions.
所以我想我应该把这个卷绕成一个。
So you can have convolutions, um,
所以你可以有卷积，嗯，
with a kernel size of one and when you first see that,
内核大小为1，当你第一次看到它时，
it seems like that makes no sense whatsoever because the whole idea
似乎完全没有任何意义，因为整个想法
of a convolution was I was taking this patch and calculating something from it.
卷积的是我正在接受这个补丁并从中计算一些东西。
If I'm not looking at any other words,
如果我不看任何其他的话，
surely I'm calculating nothing.
我当然没有计算任何东西。
But what actually happens in the size one convolution,
但实际上在一个卷积中发生了什么，
is if you have a number of channels that
如果你有多个频道
sort of in a previous layer if you'd calculated whatever it was,
如果你计算它是什么，在前一层中排序，
32 channels or something like that.
32个频道或类似的东西。
What the one by one convolution is doing is acting as
一个接一个的卷积所做的就是充当
a tiny little embedded fully-connected network over those channels.
这些通道上的一个小型嵌入式全连接网络。
And so you're sort of doing a
所以你有点做
position specific fully-connected network,
位置特定的全连接网络，
um, in- for each row of your data.
嗯，in-为您的每一行数据。
And so you can do that,
所以你可以这样做，
um, for various reasons.
嗯，出于各种原因。
You can do it because you want to map down from having
你可以这样做，因为你想要从中映射下来
a lot of channels to having fewer channels or
很多频道或频道较少的渠道
you can do it just because you think another non-linearity
你可以做到这一点只是因为你认为另一种非线性
will help and this is a really cheap way to do it.
会有所帮助，这是一种非常便宜的方式。
Because the crucial thing to notice is that if you sort
因为要注意的关键是如果你排序
of put fully-connected layers over everything,
将完全连接的层放在所有东西上，
they involve a lot of parameters whereas putting in these size
它们涉及很多参数，而是放入这些尺寸
one convolutions involve very few parameters
一个卷积涉及很少的参数
because you're just doing it at the level of a single word.
因为你只是在一个单词的水平上做。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
Um, two random things and then I'll go onto my complex model.
嗯，两个随机的东西，然后我会进入我的复杂模型。
Um, this is just a sort of
嗯，这只是一种
almost a bias- aside but it just shows
几乎是偏见，但它只是显示
something different that you could do and it's something that you could play with.
你可以做的不同的东西，这是你可以玩的东西。
I mean, when we talked about machine translation,
我的意思是，当我们谈到机器翻译时，
we talk about the SIC to SIC architecture that was introduced in
我们讨论了SIC到SIC架构的介绍
2014 and has been very successful for machine translation.
2014年，机器翻译非常成功。
But actually, the year before that came out,
但事实上，在那之前的一年，
um, there was a paper, um,
嗯，有一篇论文，嗯，
doing neural machine translation by Nal Kalchbrenner and Phil Blunsom in the UK.
由Nal Kalchbrenner和Phil Blunsom在英国进行神经机器翻译。
And this sort of was actually essentially
而这种实际上基本上就是这样
the first neural machine translation paper of the modern era.
现代第一个神经机器翻译论文。
If you dig back far enough,
如果你挖得足够远，
there are actually a couple of people that tried to use
实际上有几个人试图使用
neural networks for machine translation
用于机器翻译的神经网络
in the '80s and '90s but this was sort of the first one that restarted it,
在80年代和90年代，但这是第一个重新启动它，
and they didn't actually use a SIC to SIC architecture.
他们实际上并没有将SIC用于SIC架构。
So what they used was for the encoder,
所以他们使用的是编码器，
they used the convolutional neural networks.
他们使用卷积神经网络。
And so that they had a stack of convolutional neural networks that progressively shrunk
因此他们有一堆逐渐缩小的卷积神经网络
down the input and then finally pulled it to get a sentence representation,
按下输入然后最后拉它以获得句子表示，
and then they used a sequence model as the decoder.
然后他们使用序列模型作为解码器。
Um, so, um, that's sort of something that you could
嗯，那么，嗯，那是你能做到的
try in some other applications that for encoders,
尝试编码器的其他一些应用，
it's really easy to use convolutional neural networks.
使用卷积神经网络真的很容易。
There has been work on using convolutional neural networks as decoders as well,
已经有使用卷积神经网络作为解码器的工作，
though that's a little bit harder to get your brain around and isn't used nearly as much.
虽然这让你的大脑变得有点困难并且几乎没有被使用。
Then the second thing I want to mention because we'll turn to it in just a minute is so,
那么我想提到的第二件事是因为我们将在一分钟内转向它是如此，
so far we've done Convolutional models over words so that
到目前为止，我们已经完成了对文字的卷积模型
our kernels are effectively picking up
我们的内核正在有效地提升
these word n-gram units of two-word or three word sub-sequences.
这些单字n-gram单位的双字或三字子序列。
And the idea that then developed fairly soon was well maybe
那个很快就开发出来的想法也许很好
it would also be useful to use convolutions over characters.
对字符使用卷积也很有用。
So, you could run a convolutional neural network
所以，你可以运行一个卷积神经网络
over the characters of the word to try and,
试试这个词的字符，
um, generate a word embedding, um,
嗯，生成一个单词嵌入，嗯，
and this idea has been explored quite a lot, um,
这个想法已被探索了很多，嗯，
it's part of what you guys are gonna do for assignment
这是你们要为任务做的事情的一部分
five is build a character level ConvNet,
五是建立一个人物级别的ConvNet，
um, for your improved machine translation system.
嗯，为您改进的机器翻译系统。
I'm not going to say sort of a huge amount about the foundations of this today, um,
我今天不打算说这个基础很多，嗯，
because Thursday's lecture is then talking about subword models
因为星期四的讲座正在讨论子词模型
and we'll go through all the details of different subword models.
我们将详细介绍不同子字模型的所有细节。
But, I wanted to show you a con- a complex
但是，我想告诉你一个复杂的问题
convolutional neural network which is also used for text classification.
卷积神经网络，也用于文本分类。
So, essentially, the same task as Yoon Kim's model
所以，基本上和Yoon Kim的模型一样
and this model actually is built on characters,
而这个模型实际上建立在角色上，
it's not built on words.
它不是建立在文字之上的。
So, we are at the foundation of it,
所以，我们是它的基础，
um, having a word-like model.
嗯，有一个像字样的模型。
Um, so, this is a paper from 2017,
嗯，这是2017年的一篇论文，
um, by, um, the four authors shown here, um,
嗯，嗯，这里显示的四位作者，嗯，
people working at Facebook AI Research,
在Facebook AI Research工作的人，
um, in France, um, and so,
嗯，在法国，嗯，等等，
they kind of had an interesting hypothesis for
他们有一个有趣的假设
this paper which was essentially to say, that, you know,
本文主要是说，你知道，
by 2017 people who are using deep learning for vision were building really,
到2017年，正在使用深度学习视力的人正在建设，
really deep networks and fi- finding that they work much,
非常深入的网络和fi发现他们工作得很多，
much better for vision tasks.
视觉任务要好得多。
So, essentially to some extend,
所以，基本上在某种程度上，
the breakthrough was these guys that once these ideas that emerged,
突破是这些家伙，一旦出现这些想法，
it then proved that it wasn't just that you could build a six layer or an eight layer,
然后它证明了你不仅可以构建一个六层或八层，
um, Convolutional Neural Network for vision tasks.
嗯，用于视觉任务的卷积神经网络。
You could start building really,
你真的可以开始建设，
really deep networks for vision tasks which had tens or even hundreds of
真正深入的视觉任务网络，有几十甚至几百个
layers and that those models when trained on a lot of data proved to work even better.
这些模型在经过大量数据培训后证明工作得更好。
So, um, if that's what's in your head and you then looked,
所以，嗯，如果这就是你头脑中的东西然后你看了，
look at what was and indeed is happening in natural language processing,
看看自然语言处理中发生了什么，实际上发生了什么，
the observation is, you know,
你知道，观察是
these NLP people are kind of pathetic,
这些NLP人有点可怜，
they claim they're doing deep learning but they're still working with three layer LSTMs.
他们声称他们正在深入学习，但他们仍在使用三层LSTM。
Surely, we can make some progress, um,
当然，我们可以取得一些进展，嗯，
by building really deep networks that kinda look like vision networks and using them,
通过构建看起来像视觉网络并使用它们的真正深度网络，
um, for natural language processing goals.
嗯，用于自然语言处理目标。
And so, that is precisely what they said about doing.
所以，这正是他们所说的。
So, that they designed and built really deep network which sort of looks like a vision stack,
所以，他们设计并构建了一个非常深的网络，看起来像一个视觉堆栈，
um, as a convolutional neural network that is built over characters.
嗯，作为一个基于角色构建的卷积神经网络。
Um, so, I've got the picture of it here but sufficiently deep that it's fitting it on
嗯，所以，我已经在这里得到了它的图片，但足够深，以至于它适合它
the slide and making it readable [LAUGHTER] is a little bit
幻灯片并使其可读[大笑]是一点点
of a challenge but we can try and look at this.
挑战，但我们可以尝试看看这个。
So, at the bottom,
所以，在底部，
we have the text, um,
我们有文字，嗯，
which is a sequence of characters and so, um,
这是一系列人物，所以，嗯，
for the text, um, so,
对于文本，嗯，所以，
when people do vision object recognition on
当人们做视觉对象识别时
pictures normally all the pictures are made the same size.
图片通常所有图片都是相同的大小。
Right. You make every picture 300 pixels by 300 pixels or something like that.
对。您可以将每张图片设置为300像素乘300像素或类似的图像。
So, they do exactly the same for NLP, um,
所以，他们对NLP完全一样，嗯，
they have a size, um,
他们有一个大小，嗯，
for their document which is 1024 characters.
他们的文件是1024个字符。
If it's longer than that they truncate it and keep the first part.
如果它比它长，它们会截断它并保留第一部分。
If it's shorter than that they pad it until it's of
如果它比它短，那么它们会填充它直到它
size 1024 and then they're gonna stick it into their stack.
大小1024然后他们会把它粘在他们的堆栈中。
So, the first part is that for each character,
所以，第一部分是每个角色，
they're going to learn a character embedding now and
他们现在要学习一个人物嵌入
their character embeddings are of dimensionality 16.
他们的角色嵌入具有维度16。
So, that the piece of text is now 16 by 1024, um, so,
那么，那段文字现在是16乘1024，嗯，所以，
they're going to stick that through a convolutional layer where
他们会通过卷积层来坚持下去
you've got kernel size of three and 64 output channels.
你有三个和64个输出通道的内核大小。
So you now have something that's 64 times of 1024 in size.
所以你现在拥有的是64倍大小的64倍。
You now stick this through a convolutional block.
你现在通过卷积块来解决这个问题。
I'll explain the details of that convolutional block on the next slide but,
我将在下一张幻灯片中解释卷积块的细节，但是，
you should be thinking of that ResNet picture I showed earlier where you
你应该想到我之前在你所展示的ResNet图片
can either be going through some convolutions or taking this optional shortcut.
可以通过一些卷积或采取这个可选的快捷方式。
Another ResNet, another residual block
另一个ResNet，另一个残留块
where you can be going through convolutions are an optional shortcut,
您可以通过卷积进行选择的快捷方式，
um, they're then doing local pooling in the same way people typically do envision.
嗯，他们正在按照人们通常设想的方式进行本地汇集。
So, commonly what people do in vision systems
所以，通常是人们在视觉系统中所做的事情
is you are sort of shrinking the size of the images, um,
你有点缩小图像的大小，嗯，
by doing pooling that halves the dimensions in each direction.
通过汇集将每个方向的尺寸减半。
But, at the same time,
但是，与此同时，
you do that in your neural network,
你在你的神经网络中做到这一点，
you expand the number of channels,
你扩展了频道数​​量，
and so you make it deeper in terms of the number of
所以你在数量方面做得更深
channels at the same time as you make it smaller in the x,
在x中缩小通道的同时，
y size of the image.
y图像的大小。
So, they do exactly the same apart from these one-dimensional convolutions.
因此，除了这些一维卷积之外，它们完全相同。
So, before we had 64 channels in our 1024 character,
所以，在我们的1024个字符中有64个通道之前，
um, embedding, um, document.
嗯，嵌入，嗯，文件。
So, now we pool it, um, so,
那么，现在我们汇集它，嗯，所以，
we're going to have 512 positions which are sort of like pairs of characters,
我们将有512个位置，有点像一对字符，
um, but we now have 128 channels
嗯，但我们现在有128个频道
and then they kind of repeat that over and over again, right?
然后他们一遍又一遍地重复一遍，对吧？
So, there are two more convolutional blocks which I'll
所以，我还有两个卷积块
explain more but they're sort of residual blocks.
解释更多，但它们是残留块。
They pool it again and they do exactly the same thing.
他们再次汇集它们，它们完全相同。
So, now there are 256, um,
那么，现在有256个，嗯，
positions which are like four character blocks and they have 256 channels,
像四个字符块一样的位置，它们有256个通道，
um, I can't point high enough but they repeat that again and they pool again.
嗯，我不能说得够高，但他们又重复了一遍，然后他们再次聚集。
So, now they've got, um,
那么，现在他们已经拥有了，嗯，
128 positions which are about eight characters
128个位置，大约8个字符
each and they have 512 channels representing that.
每个，他们有512个通道代表。
They pool again, they have convolutional blocks again, um,
他们再次聚集，他们再次卷积，嗯，
then lo and behold because I said that even the
然后，因为我说甚至是
weird ideas are going to turn up, right up there,
奇怪的想法会出现，就在那里，
they're doing k max pooling and they're keeping the eight strongest values,
他们正在进行k max汇集，他们保持着八个最强的值，
um, in each channel.
嗯，在每个频道。
Um, and so at that point,
嗯，等等，
they've got something of size 512 by eight, um, so,
它们的尺寸是512×8，嗯，所以，
sort of like eight of the eight character sequences
有点像八个字符序列中的八个
have been deemed important to the classification and they're
被认为对分类很重要，他们是
kept but they sort per channel and there are 512 of them
保持，但他们按通道排序，其中有512个
you're then putting that through three fully connected layers.
然后你将它穿过三个完全连接的层。
So, typically vision systems at the top
因此，通常顶部的视觉系统
have a couple of fully connected layers at the end,
最后有几个完全连接的层，
um, and the very last one of those,
嗯，最后一个，
is effectively sort of feeding into your Softmax.
实际上有点像喂你的Softmax。
So, it's size 2,048 times the number of
所以，它的大小是数量的2,048倍
classes which might just be positive negative two class unlike the topical classes.
与主题类不同的类可能只是正面的两个类。
Um, so, yeah, so it's essentially like
嗯，是的，是的，所以它基本上就像
a vision stack but they're going to use it for language.
视觉堆栈，但他们将把它用于语言。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So, the bit that I hand quite explained was
所以，我用手解释的那一点是
these convolutional blocks but it sort of looks like the picture that we had before or,
这些卷积块但它看起来像我们之前的图片或者，
um, departments slightly more complicated.
嗯，部门稍微复杂一些。
So you're doing, um,
所以你在做，恩，
a convolutional block of size three
三个卷积块
convolutions some number of channels depending on where you are in the sequence.
根据您在序列中的位置，对一些通道进行卷积。
You're then putting it through a batch norm as we just
然后你就像我们一样，通过一个批量规范
talked about putting it through a ReLu non-linearity,
谈到通过ReLu非线性，
repeating all those three things again or remember there
再次重复所有这三件事或记住那里
was this sort of skipped connection that went right around the outside of this block.
是这种跳过的连接，就在这个街区的外面。
And so this is sort of a residual style block, um, so,
所以这是一种残余的样式块，嗯，所以，
that's the kind of complex architecture you can put together and
这是你可以组合在一起的那种复杂的架构
try in your final projects if you dare in PyTorch.
如果你敢在PyTorch中尝试你的最终项目。
Um, yeah, um, so,
嗯，是的，嗯，所以，
for experiments so- so one of
对于实验，所以其中一个
the things that they were interested in and wanted to make a point of is well some
他们感兴趣的东西，并希望提出一些观点
of these traditional sentence and
这些传统句子和
text classification datasets have been used in other papers
文本分类数据集已用于其他论文
like Yoon Kim's paper are effectively quite small.
像Yoon Kim的论文实际上非常小。
So, something like that Rotten Tomatoes dataset is actually only 10,000 examples, 5,000,
那么，Rotten Tomatoes数据集实际上只有10,000个例子，5,000个，
positive 5,000 negative and they sort of have
积极的5000负，他们有点
the idea that just like ImageNet was needed for
需要像ImageNet一样的想法
deep learning models to really show their worth and vision
深入学习模式，真正展现自己的价值和愿景
that probably does show the value of a huge model like that.
这可能确实显示了像这样的巨大模型的价值。
Um, you need to have really big datasets.
嗯，你需要拥有非常大的数据集。
So, they get some much bigger,
所以，他们会变得更大，
um, text classification datasets.
嗯，文本分类数据集。
So, here's an Amazon review positive-negative dataset, um,
那么，这是亚马逊评论的正负数据集，嗯，
with which they have sort of 3,6 million documents,
他们有360万份文件，
um, Yelp reviews 650,000 documents.
嗯，Yelp评论了650,000份文件。
So much bigger datasets,
这么大的数据集，
um, and here are their experiments.
嗯，这是他们的实验。
Okay. So, the numbers at the top, uh,
好的。那么，顶部的数字，呃，
for the different datasets of the best previous result printed in the literature,
对于文献中印刷的最佳结果的不同数据集，
and then if you read the, um,
如果你读了，嗯，
footnotes, um, there are a few things that they want to sort of star.
脚注，嗯，有一些他们想要的东西是明星。
So, the ones that have a star next to them use
那么，那些旁边有星星的人就会使用它们
an external thesaurus which they don't use. [NOISE]
他们不使用的外部词库。 [噪声]
And the Yang method, um,
杨方法，嗯，
use some special techniques as well that I cut off.
使用一些我切断的特殊技术。
Um, and the other thing to mention is these numbers,
嗯，另外要提的是这些数字，
they're error rates, so low is good.
他们是错误率，所以低是好的。
Um, so the lower you get them, the better.
嗯，你得到的越低越好。
And so then these are all of their results.
所以这些都是他们的结果。
Um, and so what can you get out of these results?
嗯，那么你能从这些结果中得到什么呢？
Um, well, the first thing that you can notice is basically with these results,
嗯，你能注意到的第一件事就是这些结果，
the deeper networks are working better, right?
更深层的网络工作得更好，对吧？
So, the one I showed you,
所以，我给你看的那个，
uh, well, no, I think the one that I have the picture of this isn't the full thing.
呃，好吧，不，我认为我对此有所了解的那个并不完整。
Um, but they have ones with depth 9, 17,
嗯，但他们有深度为9,17的那个，
and 29 in terms of the number of convolutional layers,
卷积层数为29，
and the deepest one is always the one that's working best.
而最深的一个总是最好的。
So, that's a proof of deep networks.
所以，这是深度网络的证明。
Um, that didn't keep on working, um,
嗯，没有继续工作，嗯，
so an interesting footnote here is,
所以这里有一个有趣的脚注是，
um, I guess they thought,
嗯，我猜他们想，
oh, this is cool.
哦，这很酷。
Why don't we try an even deeper one that has 47 layers and see how well that works?
为什么我们不尝试更深层次的47层，看看它有多好？
And, I mean, the results were sort of interesting for that.
而且，我的意思是，结果对此很有意思。
So, for the 47 layer one,
那么，对于47层一，
it worked a fraction worse than this one.
它的工作比这个差一点。
Um, so in one sense you,
嗯，从某种意义上说，你，
they showed the result of sort of residual layers work really well.
他们表明残留层的结果非常好。
So, they did an experiment of let's try to train
所以，他们做了一个让我们尝试训练的实验
a 47-layer network without using residual connections.
47层网络，不使用剩余连接。
And, well, it was a lot worse.
而且，情况要糟糕得多。
The numbers went down about two percent.
这个数字下降了大约2％。
And they trained one with residual connections,
他们训练了一个残余连接，
and the fact of the matter is the numbers were just a teeny weeny bit worse.
事实上这个数字只是一个小小的变弱。
They were sort of 0,1 of a percent worse.
他们有点差0,1％。
So, you know, they sort of work just about as well.
所以，你知道，他们的工作也差不多。
But, nevertheless, that's kind of different to the situation in vision,
但是，尽管如此，这与视力状况有所不同，
because for the sort of residual networks that people are using in vision,
因为对于人们在视觉中使用的那种残余网络，
this is sort of like the very minimum depth that people use.
这有点像人们使用的最小深度。
So, if you're using residual networks in vision typically,
所以，如果你通常在视觉中使用剩余网络，
you might use ResNet-34.
你可以使用ResNet-34。
If you're really short on memory and want to have a small model,
如果你真的缺乏记忆力并希望拥有一个小型号，
but you just know you'd get better results if you used ResNet-50,
但是如果你使用ResNet-50，你只知道你会得到更好的结果，
and in fact, if you used ResNet-101 it'd work even better again.
事实上，如果你使用ResNet-101，它的工作效果会更好。
Um, and so that somehow, you know,
嗯，不知何故，你知道，
whether it's got to do with the different nature of
是否与它的不同性质有关
language or the amounts of data or something,
语言或数据或其他东西，
you haven't yet gone to the same depth that you can in vision.
你还没有达到你在视觉中所能达到的同样深度。
Um, but other results, um,
嗯，但其他结果，嗯，
so the other thing they're comparing here is that they're comparing
所以他们在这里比较的另一件事就是他们在比较
three different ways of sort of stringing things down.
三种截然不同的方式。
So, you could be using, um,
所以，你可以使用，嗯，
the stride in the Convolution,
卷积中的步伐，
you can be using local MaxPooling,
你可以使用本地MaxPooling，
and you could be using KMaxPooling.
你可以使用KMaxPooling。
Um, and they're general,
嗯，他们是一般的，
they're slightly different numbers as you can see.
你可以看到他们的数字略有不同。
Each one, um, wins and one, uh,
每一个，嗯，赢一个，呃，
at least one of these datasets or actually at least two of these datasets.
这些数据集中的至少一个或实际上至少两个这些数据集。
But not only does MaxPooling win for four of the datasets,
但MaxPooling不仅赢得了四个数据集，
if you sort of look at the numbers,
如果你看看数字，
MaxPooling always does pretty well.
MaxPooling总是做得很好。
Because MaxPooling does pretty well here,
因为MaxPooling在这里做得很好，
whereas the convolutional stride works badly,
卷积的步幅很糟糕，
and over here MaxPooling works pretty well,
在这里MaxPooling工作得很好，
and the, um, KMaxPooling works kind of badly.
而且，嗯，KMaxPooling的工作有点糟糕。
So, their recommendation at the end of the day is you should always use, um,
所以，他们在一天结束时的推荐是你应该总是使用，嗯，
just MaxPooling of a simple kind,
只是一个简单的MaxPooling，
that that seems to be fine,
这看起来很好，
um, and nothing else.
嗯，没别的。
Um, it's actually worth the trouble of thinking about doing.
嗯，实际上值得考虑做的事情。
Okay. Um, was there any other conclusions I wanted to say?
好的。嗯，我想说的还有其他任何结论吗？
Okay. Um, I think that was most of that.
好的。嗯，我认为那是其中的大部分内容。
I guess their overall message is you can build super good, um,
我猜他们的整体信息是你可以建立超级好，嗯，
text classification systems using ConvNets,
使用ConvNets的文本分类系统，
and you should take away that message.
你应该带走那条信息。
Okay. So, there are just a couple of minutes left.
好的。所以，还剩下几分钟。
There was sort of one other thing that I wanted to mention,
还有一件我想提到的事情，
but I think I'll just sort of mention it very quickly,
但我想我会很快提到它，
and you can look in more detail if you want to.
如果你愿意，你可以查看更详细的信息。
So, we sort of have this situation
所以，我们有这种情况
that re- recurrent neural networks are a very standard building block for NLP,
反复神经网络是NLP非常标准的构建块，
but they have this big problem that they just don't parallelize well.
但他们有一个很大的问题，他们只是不能很好地并行化。
And the way we get fast computation deep learning is we find
我们发现，我们获得快速计算深度学习的方式
things that parallelize well so that we can stick them on GPUs.
并行化的东西，以便我们可以将它们粘贴在GPU上。
GPUs only are fast if they can be simultaneously doing the same computation many times,
如果GPU可以同时多次执行相同的计算，则它们很快，
which is sort of trivial for a convolutional neural network,
这对于卷积神经网络来说是微不足道的，
because precisely, you're doing the same comput- computation every position.
因为确切地说，你在每个位置都进行相同的计算。
But that's not what's happening in the recurrent neural network because you have to
但这不是在递归神经网络中发生的事情，因为你必须这样做
work out the value of position one
弄清楚第一位的价值
before you can start to calculate the value of position two,
在你开始计算位置二的值之前，
which is used for the value of position three.
用于第三位的值。
Um, so this was a piece of work, um,
嗯，所以这是一件工作，嗯，
done by sometimes CS224N co-instructor
有时是CS224N共同指导员完成的
Richard Socher and some of his people at Salesforce Research
Richard Socher和他在Salesforce Research的一些人
on saying, how can we get the best of both worlds?
说，我们怎样才能充分利用这两个世界？
How can we get something that's kind of like a
我们怎样才能得到类似于某种东西的东西
recurrent neural network, but doesn't have the bad computational properties?
递归神经网络，但没有糟糕的计算属性？
And so the idea that they had was, well,
所以他们的想法是，嗯，
rather than doing the standard LSTM style thing where you're calculating, you know,
你知道，而不是做你正在计算的标准LSTM风格的东西，
an updated candidate value and your gates in terms of the preceding time slice,
更新的候选值和前一时间片的门，
maybe what instead we could do is we could stick a relation between time
或许我们可以做的是我们可以在时间之间建立关系
minus 1 and time into the MaxPooling layer of a convolutional neural network.
减去1并进入卷积神经网络的MaxPooling层的时间。
So, we're sort of calculating a candidate and a forget gate and an output gate.
所以，我们有点计算候选人，忘记门和输出门。
But these, these candidate and the, um,
但是这些，这些候选人和嗯，
gated values are done inside the pooling layer via compute,
门控值通过compute在池化层内完成，
um, via, um, uh, uh, convolutional operation.
嗯，通过，嗯，呃，卷积操作。
So, it sort of get,
所以，它有点得到，
it doesn't, it, you know,
它没有，它，你知道，
if there's no free lunch you can't get true recurrence and not pay the penalty.
如果没有免费的午餐，你就无法获得真正的复发，也不会支付罚金。
This is giving you sort of a pseudo-recurrence because you are
这会给你一些伪复发，因为你是
modeling an association between adjacent elements at each time slice,
在每个时间片对相邻元素之间的关联建模，
but it's sort of just worked out locally rather than being carried forward,
但它只是在当地制定而不是继续推进，
um, in one layer.
嗯，在一层。
But sort of what they found is,
但他们发现的是，
if you made your networks deeper using this idea,
如果你使用这个想法让你的网络更深入，
well then, you sort of start to, again,
那么，你又开始了，
expand your window of influence.
扩大你的影响力窗口。
So, you got a certain amount of information being carried forward.
所以，你得到了一定数量的信息。
Um, so, their conclusions was that you could sort of
嗯，所以，他们的结论是你可以那样
build these kind of models and get them to work,
构建这些模型并让它们工作，
you know, not necessarily better actually on this slide,
你知道，在这张幻灯片上实际上并不一定更好，
um, it says often better.
嗯，它说通常更好。
Um, you can get them to work kind of as well as an LSTM does,
嗯，你可以让他们和LSTM一样工作，
but you could get them to work much faster because you're avoiding
但你可以让他们更快地工作，因为你正在避免
the standard recurrent operation and keeping it as something that you can parallelize,
标准的循环操作并将其保存为可以并行化的东西，
um, in the MaxPooling operations.
嗯，在MaxPooling操作中。
Um, yes, so that was a kind of
嗯，是的，所以这是一种
an interesting alternative way of sort of trying to get some of the benefits.
一种有趣的替代方式，试图获得一些好处。
I think long-term this isn't the idea that's going to end up winning out.
我认为长期来看，这不是最终会赢得胜利的想法。
And so next week we're going to talk about transformer networks,
下周我们将讨论变压器网络，
which actually seems to be the idea that's gained the most steam at the moment.
这实际上似乎是目前获得最多蒸汽的想法。
Okay. I'll stop there for today. Thanks a lot.
好的。我今天就到此为止。非常感谢。